<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hobby | Nicks Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/categories/hobby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-08T13:00:12-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicholas Lau]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Schemer by Daniel Friedman and Matthias Felleisen]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/04/03/little-schemer/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-03T13:51:55-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/04/03/little-schemer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Under Construction</h2>

<p>With the exception of a quarter or two, University exclusively taught in the Object Oriented Procedural Paradigm. And while that will always feel like home&hellip; I don&rsquo;t spend that much time at home. It&rsquo;s nice to get out of your comfort zone, and go explore and learn new things. So I decided to pick up Little Schemer and gain some insight into Recursion and the Functional programming paradigm.</p>

<p>While learning JavaScript I watched Douglas Crockford&rsquo;s lecture on JavaScript: <a href="https://goo.gl/hsLTwc">Act III: Function the Ultimate</a>. In this talk he recommended Little Schemer, promising that it would &ldquo;Change the way you think, and there aren&rsquo;t a lot of books that will do that&rdquo;. It wasn&rsquo;t the first time that I had heard of the book, but this gave me to push to pick it up.</p>

<p>I can say happily that it did not disappoint. I&rsquo;ve always been fascinated by graphs and how easily that can model real world problems. And this book has pushed me towards some key insights there&hellip; which I will have to write a full blog post on in the future. But to put in a words I never thought I&rsquo;d say: I now find it easier to think in recursion - since I know that if I can cover all the possible cases I&rsquo;ll eventually reach the solution.</p>

<p>So without further ado, here are some of my favorite quotes from Little Schemer by Daniel Friedman and Matthias Felleisen:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Note that Little Schemer isn&rsquo;t normal book, it&rsquo;s based on lecture slides and works in a Q&amp;A format. [(action) Put a picture] as an example. It also assumes zero knowledge of Scheme. So it starts very easy and builds you up from the basics. And eventually gets to some really cool stuff towards the end [spoiler tag]: Collectors, Applicative-Order Y-Combinator, Interpreter</p>

<p>Little Schemer, pg 23</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;What is the next question? else.&rdquo;
&ldquo;Why is else the next question? Because we do not need to ask any more questions.&rdquo;
&ldquo;Why do we not need to ask any more questions? Because a list can be empty, can have an atom in the first position, or can have a list in the first position&rdquo;
&ldquo;Is else really a question? Yes, else is a question whose value is always true.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Fourth Commandment:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Always change at least one argument while recurring. It must be changed to be closer to termination. The changing argument must be tested in the terminating condition: when using cdr, test termination with null?&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 83,</p>

<blockquote><p>Because all *-functions work on lists that are either:
  -empty
  -an atom consed onto a list, or
  -a list consed onto a list</p></blockquote>

<p>Recursive way of looking at short-circuting, pg 88</p>

<blockquote><p>Question: Do you remember what (or &hellip;) does?
Anaser: (or &hellip;) asks questions one at a time until it finds one that is true. Then (or&hellip;) stops, makeing its value true. If it cannot find a true argument, the value of (or &hellip;) is false
And the opposite for (and &hellip;)</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 91, Sixth Commandment</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;But then the  says: "Simplify only after the function is correct&rdquo;, so I shouldn&rsquo;t have skipped to the next iteration, and should have done the first version first because its easier to verify"</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 98</p>

<blockquote><p>Why is (n + 3) a good representation?
Because
1. (n + 3) is an S-expresssion. It can therefore serve as an argument for a function.
2. It structurally resembles n + 3</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 107, Eight Commandment</p>

<blockquote><p>Use help functions to abstract from representations</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 107</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Numbers are representations? Yes. For example 4 stands for the concept four. We chose that symbol because we are accustomed to arabic representations.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 127</p>

<blockquote><p>What kind of values can functions return? Lists and atoms (and functions)
Lambdas (currying) were discovered by Moses Schonfinkel and Haskell B Curry</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 150</p>

<blockquote><p>Can you guess what sorn stands for? Nope. Symbol or Number
Unnatural Recursion, does not recur on a part of lat (but on a result of a passed around function)</p></blockquote>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t collect a lot of quotes from the last 3 chapters (collectors, Y-Comb, intepreter), but here are some of my notes:</p>

<blockquote><p>Really very mind expanding, chapter 9 and 10 are brutal. I thought 8 was hard with collectors but I got that in 2 reads. 9 I&rsquo;ve already read twice and it still blows my mind.
Wow this book is going to break my brain, really cool. Using tables for stack frames and language (identifiers to primitivies/values)
(Stack overflow) Long story short, it allows you to implement recursion in a language that doesn&rsquo;t necessarily support it natively.</p></blockquote>

<p>Y-combinator steps in my words</p>

<blockquote><p>length loses define, redefine length over and over with eternity as end point (use eternity because you lost length)
remove repetitions with create mk-length that creates length-like function
don&rsquo;t need eternity because you never reach it
pass mk-length to itself so it never runs out, but isn&rsquo;t infinite because of base case
make mk-length mk-length into a lambda that returns a function, so you can abstract it out and separate it from length</p></blockquote>

<p>(action)
Look through chapters 8-10 for some quotes</p>

<p>Learning more, recommends:</p>

<blockquote><p>Polya, George. How to Solve it</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commandline Shenanigans]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/07/shenanigans/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-07T14:57:53-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/07/shenanigans</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Table of Contents</h3>

<p>Test</p>

<!-- more -->



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mindfulness in Plain English by Henepola Gunaratana]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/04/mindfulness-in-plan-english/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-04T12:51:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/04/mindfulness-in-plan-english</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Under Construction</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always been interested in meditation. Having grown up in the Silicon Valley, I&rsquo;ve found that the heart of the tech world has an ironic obsession with spirituality. While not busy mining the finest 1&rsquo;s and 0&rsquo;s from the Silcion Valley Mines, idols like Steve Jobs were well known for their obsession with spirituality.</p>

<p>About a year or two ago I began to read more about meditation and started integrating a basic form of deep breathing into my life. After backpacking around Southeast and East Asia for a few months this amateur interest gained steam. Theravada Buddhism is very popular in Southeast Asia, so during my month in Vietnam I had lots of exposure to it while visiting shrines or hanging out with natives. Zen Buddhism is more poplular in East Asia, which matches my ethnicity (I&rsquo;m half Chinese and half Japanese).</p>

<p>After reading around online and practicing the basics I found - r/meditation is a fantastic resource! I decided I wanted to dive depper into the Theravada school of Buddhism. This was because it was more based on the scriptures and thus can be self-studied while Zen tends to need a mentor or teacher to guide you. Thus, I decided to read Mindfulness in Plain English, a well known and practical book on Theravada meditation.</p>

<p>Here are some of my favorite quotes from Mindfulness in Plain English by Henepola Gunaratana. These first four are actually ideas that I keep onhand and reread on a weekly basis.</p>

<p>pg 8</p>

<blockquote><p>Cool ideas in how you grasp at the happy 10%, reject the sad 10% and ignore the neutral 80% (Retrieve actual Quote from book)</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 29 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;That initial perception will spark pleasant, unpleasant or neutral feelings. That is a universal phenomenon. It occurs in the mind of others just as it does in his, and he should see that clearly. Following these feelings various reactions may arise. He may feel greed, lust, or jealousy. He may feel fear, worry, restlessness or boredom. These reactions are universal. He simple notes them and then generalizes. He should realize that these reactions are normal human responses and can arise in anybody.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 11</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Like the breath, mental states have three stages: beginning, middle, and end. Often when you realize your concentration has drifted and you&rsquo;ve been thinking awhile&hellip; it&rsquo;s cause the mental state is near its end. You have to learn to find it at the beginning (as it rises out of your unconscious) and gently watch it through to its end.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>More from Chapter 11</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;We are constantly conceptualizing, to solve our problems, to communicate. But with mindfulness you examine before conceptualization, and look at the pure nature of mental phenomena.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>And many more to follow below!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I have a friend who&rsquo;s an actor LA, this quote reminded me of my conversations of him. As well as showing a practial application of mindfulness - that you can change who you are with it. pg 25</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Tantric&hellip; The self-concept or ego is nothing more than a set of reactions and mental images that are artificially pasted to the flowing process of pure awareness&hellip; The student is given a particular religious image to meditate upon, for examle, one of the deities from the tantric pantheon&hellip;. She takes off her own identity and puts on another. During the process, she is able to watch the way in which the ego is constructed and put in place. She comes to recognize the arbitrary nature of all egos, including her own, and she excapes from bondage to the ego. She is left in a state where she may have an ego if she so chosses - either her own or whichever other she might wish - or she can make do without one&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 25,</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The object of vipassana practice is to learn to see the truths of impermanence, unsatisfactoriness, and selflessness of phenomena. We think we are doing this already, but that is an illusion. It comes from the fact that we are paying so little attention to the ongoing surge of our own life experiences that we might just as well be asleep. We are simply not paying enough attention to nootice that we are not paying attention. It is another Catch-22&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 27 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;10. Don&rsquo;t ponder: You don&rsquo;t need to figure everything out. Discursive thinking won&rsquo;t free you from the trap. In mediation, the mind is purified naturally by mindfulness, by wordless bare attention. Habitual deliberation is not necessary to eliminate those things that are keeping you in bondage. All that is necessary is a clear, non-conceptual perception of what they are and how they work. That alone is sufficient to dissolve them. Concepts and reasoning just get in the way. Don&rsquo;t think. See.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 29 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;When the meditator perceives any sensory object, he is not to dwell upon it in the ordinary egotistical way. He should rather examine the very process of perception itself. He should watch the feelings that arise and the mental activities that follow. He should note the changes that occur in his own consciousness as a result. In watching all these phenomena, the meditator must be aware of the universality of what he is seeing. That initial perception will spark pleasant, unpleasant or neutral feelings. That is a universal phenomenon. It occurs in the mind of others just as it does in his, and he should see that clearly. Following these feelings various reactions may arise. He may feel greed, lust, or jealousy. He may feel fear, worry, restlessness or boredom. These reactions are universal. He simple notes them and then generalizes. He should realize that these reactions are normal human responses and can arise in anybody.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 29 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;At that point, without trying to confuse the feeling with the mental formations, we should isolate the feeling as feeling and watch it mindfully. Feeling is one of the seven universal mental factors. The other six are contact, perception, mental formations, concentration, life force, and awareness.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 34 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;d) The fourth method is to take a long breath. When the lungs are full, mentally count "one&rdquo; and breath out completely until the lungs are empty of fresh air. Then count mentally &ldquo;two&rdquo;. Take a long breath again and count &ldquo;three&rdquo; and breathe completely out as before. When the lungs are empty of fresh air, count mentally &ldquo;four&rdquo;. Count your breath in this manner up to ten. Then count backward from ten to one. Count again from one to ten and then ten to one."</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 5</p>

<blockquote><p>The practice: Start with Empathy and loving kindness, Three deep breaths to concentrate, then tip of nostrils, then find your sign</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 93</p>

<blockquote><p>Pain is inevitable, suffering is not</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 10 on dealing with problems</p>

<blockquote><p>Blissful feeling or sense of failure are actually drawing you away from mindfulness</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 113</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Thoughts of greed cover everything connected with desire, from outright avarice for material gain, all the way down to a subtle need to be respected as a moral person. Thoughts of hatred run the gamut from petty peevishness to murderous rage. Delusion covers everything from daydreaming through actual hallucinations. Generosity cancels greed. Benevolence and compassion cancel hatred. You can find a specific antidote for any troubling thought if you just think about it a while.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 11, dealing with distractions 2</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Temporarily meditate on distractions. Wordlessly answer these questions: what is it, how strong is it, how long does it last&rdquo;
&ldquo;Like the breath, mental states have three stages: beginning, middle, and end. Often when you realize you&rsquo;re concentration has drifted and you&rsquo;ve been thinking awhile&hellip; it&rsquo;s cause the mental state is near its end. You have to learn to find it at the beginning (as it rises out of your unconscious) and gently watch it through to its end&rdquo;
&ldquo;We are constantly conceptualizing, to solve our problems, to communicate. But with mindfulness you examine before conceptualization, and look at the pure nature of mental phenomena&rdquo;
&ldquo;Realize that you have been off the track for such and such a length of time and go back to the breath. There is no need for any negative reaction at all. The very act of realizing that you have been off the track is an active awareness. It is an exercise of pure mindfulness all by itself.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 14, Mindfulness vs Concentration</p>

<blockquote><p>A distinction that I hadn&rsquo;t realized:
Mindfulness is more important overall, but concentration is what you have to focus on in the begininng. Or else monkey mind will overwhelm mindfulness with random chatter. Overall, mindfulness will lead to better concentration by making you aware that your concentration has slipped and allowing you to re-engage it</p></blockquote>

<p>The Power of Loving Friendliness, The Four Sublime States</p>

<blockquote><p>Loving Friendliness, Compassion, Appreciative Joy, and Equanimity
Uses the metaphor of having a child. Before the child is born, it&rsquo;s already being cared for regardless of its actions. This is metta or loving friendliness. As the infant starts exploring the world, it will hurt itself sometimes, and the parents feel the same pain. This is compassion. When the child gets older and goes to school, it will have successes, and the parents will feel happiness for it. This is appreciative joy. Finally, when the child goes out on his own,  the parents will practice equanimity: the appreciate that they have done all they could for the child but no longer steer the outcome of the child&rsquo;s life</p></blockquote>

<p>Appendix: the Context of the Tradition</p>

<blockquote><p>Vipassana is &ldquo;insight&rdquo;, a clear awareness of exactly what is happening as it happens
Samatha can be translated as &ldquo;concentration&rdquo; or &ldquo;tranquillity,&rdquo; and is a state in which the mind is focused only on one item, brought to rest, and not allowed to wander"
This book focuses on Theravada Buddhishm, common in South and Southeast Asia. The other main school is Mahaya Buddhism which is more common in East Asia, mainly the Zen school. A quick google search shows that Theravada is better for my situation, although it doesn&rsquo;t line up with my heritage. The reasons for this is that it is more based on scriptures so less based on teacher</p></blockquote>

<p>As a disclaimer: I&rsquo;m not a big fan of the intro, it is very preachy. Promising the solution to all lifes problems and happiness, blah blah. I feel like I&rsquo;m being sold snake oil. It mocks normal people and the way they live&hellip; for example, page 8. I HATE THIS PARAGRAPH, civilization is responsible for so much good. Technology has raised our standard of living insanely. And no people are not trying to steal my watch.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Wait a minute, though. Peace and happiness! Isn&rsquo;t that what civilization is all about? We build skyscrapers and freeways. We have paid vacations, TV sets. We provide free hospitals and sick leaves, Social Security and welfare benefits. All of that is aimed at providing some measure of peace and happiness. Yet the rate of mental illness climbs steadily, and the crime rates rise faster. The streets are crawling with delinquents and unstable individuals. Stick your arms outside the safety of your own door and somebody is very likely to steal your watch! Something is not working. A happy man does not feel driven to kill. We like to think that our society is exploiting every area of human knowledge in order to achieve peace and happiness.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MyFitnessJourney]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/18/myfitnessjourney/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-18T06:37:41-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/18/myfitnessjourney</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Under Construction</h1>

<h3>Introduction</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ll start with a disclaimer: This isn&rsquo;t a guide. This is <em>my</em> fitness journey, how I achieved <em>my</em> goals with the time and effort <em>I</em> was willing to put forth. Although, at the same time, I&rsquo;m a pretty normal guy so maybe these things will apply to you as well. Also, friends will often ask for advice so I figure I can just direct them here rather than attempt to cover everything poorly in person, and have them not retain that much.</p>

<p>This whole post could be summed up with: Eat, Sleep, Workout, Be Consistent</p>

<h3>Table of Contents</h3>

<ul>
<li>Background</li>
<li>What I used to do</li>
<li>Transition to Power Lifting</li>
<li>Studying</li>
<li>Nutrition, Lifting, Sleep, <em>Sustainability</em></li>
<li>Cutting</li>
<li>Bulking</li>
<li>Progress Pics and Body Scan results</li>
<li>Favorite Resources</li>
</ul>


<h3>Background</h3>

<p>Since June I&rsquo;ve gone from 139 lbs to 143 lbs. From:</p>

<ul>
<li>67.2 lbs of Skeletal Muscle Mass, 21.2 lbs of Body Fat Mass, with a 15.1 Body Fat percentage</li>
<li>72.3 lbs of Skeletal Muscle Mass, 16.3 lbs of Body Fat Mass, with a 11.4 Body Fat percentage</li>
</ul>


<p>Here&rsquo;s some of my lifts, I&rsquo;ve mostly moved into intermediate going on proficient territory. So I&rsquo;m pretty happy but I&rsquo;ve got a long ways to go:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th> <strong>Lift</strong>          </th>
<th> <strong>5 Rep Max (lbs)</strong> </th>
<th> <strong>Theoretical 1 Rep (lbs)</strong> </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> Back Squat        </td>
<td> 240                 </td>
<td> 280                      </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Deadlift          </td>
<td> 240                 </td>
<td> 280                      </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Bench Press       </td>
<td> 185                 </td>
<td> 225                      </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Overhead Press    </td>
<td> 115                 </td>
<td> 135                      </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Weighted Pull-up  </td>
<td> 45                  </td>
<td> 75                       </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Pendlay Row       </td>
<td> 135                 </td>
<td> 155                      </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<!-- more -->


<h3>What I used to Do</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always been casually interested in fitness. I was raised on sports, and have played the majority of sports with my friends at some point. From rugby, wrestling, wiffleball, ping pong, etc. I ran track and cross country in highschool which got me a free member ship to the gym. So I would jog over to the local gym and work out on the machines, religiously following the given Range of Motion. I would do sets of 75 ten pound dumbbell curls, pushups to feel more productive while watching the sharks or warriors play.</p>

<p>During university, I would find routines off the internet, often combining them into some strange amalgamation based on what I thought was best. I would drink whey protein, and make mediocre progress until midterms or finals came by and then start all over again. Overall, I saw little progress over the course of 4 years.</p>

<h3>Transition to Power Lifting</h3>

<p>Then I discovered power lifting. This by itself wasn&rsquo;t the most important thing, that was the resources it lead me too. But we&rsquo;ll get to that later. I picked up the beginner powerlifing routine Stronglifts 5x5s. Yes, I was still a beginner after 4 years. This routine forced me to pick up a bunch of important lifts that I had been neglecting or had been too afraid to try, such as Squats, Deadlifts, and Overhead Press. It made them easy to pick up by starting the weights very low. It provided things beyond lifts and reps, such as when to deload.</p>

<h3>Studying</h3>

<h3>Nutrition, Lifting, Sleep, <em>Sustainability</em></h3>

<h3>Cutting</h3>

<h3>Bulking</h3>

<h3>Progress Pics and Body Scan results</h3>

<h3>Favorite Resources</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://examine.com/">Examine</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fitness">r/fitness</a></li>
<li><a href="http://symmetricstrength.com/">Symmetric Strength</a></li>
<li><a href="http://iifym.com/iifym-calculator/">iifym</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favorite Tools and Tricks]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/03/favorite-tools-and-tricks/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-03T00:26:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/03/favorite-tools-and-tricks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was showing two of my engineer buddies something on my laptop when I realized they didn&rsquo;t know how to shortcut between tabs. It blew my mind that people don&rsquo;t know these things, which got my thinking about all the little tips and tricks I&rsquo;ve picked up over the years. I ended up making a list&hellip; so I figured I might as well share it. I&rsquo;ll throw on a quick summary for why I use all these things. For example:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Google</em>, Really really good search engine. A strong alternative to Bing if you&rsquo;re willing to give up the $125/year that Microsoft will give you for clicks.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ve mostly found these through annoyance at minor inconveniences, whether they be multiple keystrokes or the laborious task of moving my hands to the keyboard and back.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Chrome Shortcuts</h3>

<ul>
<li>Remove item from search bar and history, opt+cmd+del</li>
<li>Switching between tabs, shift+opt+{} or ctrl+shift+tab</li>
<li>Jumping between tabs, cmd+(0-9)</li>
<li>Moving to address bar, cmd+L</li>
</ul>


<h3>Gmail Shortcuts (have to enable them)</h3>

<ul>
<li>Refresh inbox, u</li>
<li>Move between messages, j/k</li>
<li>Archive and Move between messages, {/}</li>
<li>Move to search bar, /</li>
<li>Open message, o</li>
<li>Move between Folders, g+(i for inbox)(t for sent)(l for label)(s for starred)(a for all)</li>
<li>Compose, c</li>
<li>Send, cmd+enter</li>
</ul>


<h3>Chrome Extensions</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Vimium</em>, I couldn&rsquo;t live without this one. It lets you use chrome with vim inspired shortcuts. Hit &rsquo;d' to go down half a page, &lsquo;k&rsquo; to scroll up, &lsquo;gi&rsquo; to move cursor to a textarea then &lsquo;tab&rsquo; to move to the next textarea, etc.</li>
<li><em>Papaly</em>, I have two tabs pinned&hellip; gmail and papaly. Papaly lets me save links in a quick and organized manner, letting me keep my browser uncluttered.</li>
<li><em>Empty New Tab Page</em>, Because it cleans up your interface ever so slightly, &ldquo;a clean room is a clean mind&rdquo;.</li>
<li><em>Imagus</em>, hover to see full size image. Have it configured to show image on shift press.</li>
<li><em>goo.gl URL Shortener</em>, this is very particular to my workflow. Whenever I find something valuable on the internet, I&rsquo;ll throw a quick summary and it&rsquo;s goog.gl link on a plain text to review later.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Privacy</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Ghostery</em>, Ghostery blocks 3rd party trackers, make sure to disable GhostRank.</li>
<li><em>TrackMeNot</em>, clicks every ad (but doesn&rsquo;t load them) to obfuscate your actual activity.</li>
<li><em>uBlockOrigin</em>, uBlockOrigin, largely superior Adblock Plus. More efficient.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Software</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Flux</em>, reduces eyestrain by adapting your computer screen to the time of day. Takes some adjusting to. But after that you won&rsquo;t be able to live without it.</li>
<li><em>Moom</em>, window management, lets me move my windows anywhere I want with an efficient hotkey. Mandatory if you&rsquo;re working with larger monitors (I have a 27" and 24").</li>
<li><em>VPN</em>, lets me feel safe when I&rsquo;m on public wifi. Was especially useful when I backed around Asia. I personally use Private Internet Access (PIA), one of the bigger providers.</li>
<li><em>Copy Clip</em>, clipboard manager for os x. It&rsquo;s free, why not?</li>
<li><em>Google Spreadsheets</em>, have several of these setup for subjects that require more organization. Is conveniently synced between phone and computers.</li>
<li><em>Pomodoro Timer</em>, more for my workflow. I work on tasks in 30 minute chunks so its perfect.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Knowledge base</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Sublime Text</em>, have it opened with entire Dropbox directory. cmd+shift+f executes an interactive grep-like search, makes it very easy to find what I&rsquo;m looking for. cmd+t lets me quickly open whatever file I want.</li>
<li><em>Nebulous for iOS</em>, plain text editor and Dropbox compatibility. Lets me view and edit my knowledge base. Great for my todo lists and to productively kill time when I&rsquo;m waiting in line.</li>
<li><em>Dropbox</em>, keeps everything synced. Although I did have to pay for more storage.</li>
<li><em>Org mode</em>, incredible! Plan to integrate this into workflow shortly.</li>
<li><em>Evernote</em>, you all know what this is. I&rsquo;m not it&rsquo;s biggest fan, eventually I want to move to an org mode + dropbox + sublime/nebulous workflow. But for now, I use its reminders to re-expose me to particularily interesting pieces of knowledge. Huge issues include: inconvenient exporting, no multiple hierachies of notes/notebooks, ads everywhere, general bugginess.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Sublime Text</h3>

<ul>
<li>ctrl+cmd+up/down arrows, swap rows up and down.</li>
<li>ctrl+shift+up/down arrows, quickly spawn multiple cursors for some efficient editing.</li>
<li>cmd+k then cmd+b, hide/show sidebar</li>
<li>ctrl+shift+k, delete the current line your cursor is on</li>
<li>Many many more, but I don&rsquo;t want to go overboard</li>
</ul>


<h3>OS X</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Spotlight</em>, cmd+space. Let&rsquo;s you find anything on your computer quickly and conveniently. Whether it&rsquo;s an application, file, widget.</li>
<li><em>Hot Corners</em>, move the mouse to bottom left or right corner to put my laptop to sleep. Lets me take faster bathroom breaks at the coffee shop.</li>
<li>Remapping Caps to Control at OS level (Modifier Keys). Especially useful for the Command Line Interface. Who uses Caps Lock anyways.</li>
<li>PLEASE NEVER MOVE THROUGH TEXT BY HOLDING THE ARROW KEYS (and try to avoid the mouse). cmd+left/right arrows, move to beginning or end of line. option+left/right arrow, move a word at a time, similar to vim&rsquo;s &lsquo;w&rsquo; and &lsquo;b&rsquo; commands.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Peace of Mind</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Crashplan</em>, backs up my computer to a remote location every night while I&rsquo;m sleeping. I backup with my harddrive weekly for a local backup. So unless the right data center and my house burn down simultaneously I&rsquo;m fine.</li>
<li><em>Mint</em>, free personal budgeting application. I used to constantly worry about whether I was getting mischarged, having my credit cards stolen, or paying fees I shouldn&rsquo;t be. With this I can check every couple days and never have to worry.</li>
<li><em>1Password</em>, just in case I forget. Sync my keychain over dropbox so it&rsquo;s available in case of emergencies.</li>
</ul>


<h3>App Specific</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Mint Mojito</em>, improves ui for mint. You can cut out sections you don&rsquo;t want, like: recommendations, ads, etc&hellip;</li>
<li><em>Google Calendar Scroll Disabler</em>, because the trackpad is way too sensitive and I often found myself a year ahead of where I wanted to be.</li>
<li><em>The Camelizer</em>, tracks Amazon prices. Let&rsquo;s you see if you&rsquo;re getting a good deal or should wait. Can set price watches that will notify you when the price drops to what you&rsquo;re willing to pay. Along this note, using ifttt to watch rss feeds or using slickdeals deal watchers is really effective as well.</li>
<li><em>Reddit Enhancement Suite</em>, I can&rsquo;t remember what it was like to not have this.</li>
<li><em>Download FB Album mod</em>, lets you download albums off Facebook, in case they ever go out of business.</li>
<li><em>Boomerang for Gmail</em>, Lets you program mail to be sent at certain times. Nice when you&rsquo;re doing email at 3am, but want it sent out at a reasonable time.</li>
<li>Facebook: <em>News Feed Blocker</em>, <em>Facebook Unseen</em> (I know this should be in App-Specific&hellip; but for real). When you open facebook to jump on the messenger, the feed is less likely to draw you in&hellip; and unseen so that you can read messages without beening inclined to answer them until it&rsquo;s more convenient. Remember when the &lsquo;seen at 4:21&rsquo; feature was new and everyone despised it?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
