<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: writing | Nicks Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-10T15:02:12-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicholas Lau]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on Clarity]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2014/05/13/thoughts-on-clarity/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-13T23:16:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2014/05/13/thoughts-on-clarity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s why stories appeal to us. They give us the clarity and simplicity our real lives lack&rdquo; - Patrick Rothfuss. Since I love stories, whether they are from books or movies or tv&hellip; this quote struck me. However, I think that the hunt for clarity and simplicity applies beyond stories to everything that I love, to all the hobbies that I enjoy. I do not expect to ever understand life enough that I might claim that it is simple. However, I will certainly try. I feel that my best chance is to pick small pockets of life as hobbies and over a lifetime of learning, achieve a high level of understanding (or clarity).</p>

<p>I have always loved clarity. When I played hockey in high school, I loved starting a rush up the ice, all the possibilities laid bare before me. Or studying for a final as I could feel all the information consolidating, seeing how interconnected all the details were and understanding the flow of the subject matter. Thus, I loved games, learning their inner workings and obsessing over them until I could see several steps ahead. I loved learning because if you studied hard enough and read deep enough into the subject then there was no need to memorize, it would become natural and simply make sense.</p>

<p>But games come and go. The one constant has become programming, it is the ultimate hobby since I can get paid for doing it and spend my next 30-40 years exploring its nuisances under the guise of a career. I&rsquo;ll be surrounded with others who have spent decades studying and learn from them. There will be no slacking since I&rsquo;ll be disciplined to spending 40 hours a week. And yes, I will balance it with my personal life and other hobbies. Ultimately though, I see it as my greatest hope for achieving clarity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
