<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Nicks Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-08T13:00:12-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicholas Lau]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Schemer by Daniel Friedman and Matthias Felleisen]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/04/03/little-schemer/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-03T13:51:55-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/04/03/little-schemer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Under Construction</h2>

<p>With the exception of a quarter or two, University exclusively taught in the Object Oriented Procedural Paradigm. And while that will always feel like home&hellip; I don&rsquo;t spend that much time at home. It&rsquo;s nice to get out of your comfort zone, and go explore and learn new things. So I decided to pick up Little Schemer and gain some insight into Recursion and the Functional programming paradigm.</p>

<p>While learning JavaScript I watched Douglas Crockford&rsquo;s lecture on JavaScript: <a href="https://goo.gl/hsLTwc">Act III: Function the Ultimate</a>. In this talk he recommended Little Schemer, promising that it would &ldquo;Change the way you think, and there aren&rsquo;t a lot of books that will do that&rdquo;. It wasn&rsquo;t the first time that I had heard of the book, but this gave me to push to pick it up.</p>

<p>I can say happily that it did not disappoint. I&rsquo;ve always been fascinated by graphs and how easily that can model real world problems. And this book has pushed me towards some key insights there&hellip; which I will have to write a full blog post on in the future. But to put in a words I never thought I&rsquo;d say: I now find it easier to think in recursion - since I know that if I can cover all the possible cases I&rsquo;ll eventually reach the solution.</p>

<p>So without further ado, here are some of my favorite quotes from Little Schemer by Daniel Friedman and Matthias Felleisen:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Note that Little Schemer isn&rsquo;t normal book, it&rsquo;s based on lecture slides and works in a Q&amp;A format. [(action) Put a picture] as an example. It also assumes zero knowledge of Scheme. So it starts very easy and builds you up from the basics. And eventually gets to some really cool stuff towards the end [spoiler tag]: Collectors, Applicative-Order Y-Combinator, Interpreter</p>

<p>Little Schemer, pg 23</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;What is the next question? else.&rdquo;
&ldquo;Why is else the next question? Because we do not need to ask any more questions.&rdquo;
&ldquo;Why do we not need to ask any more questions? Because a list can be empty, can have an atom in the first position, or can have a list in the first position&rdquo;
&ldquo;Is else really a question? Yes, else is a question whose value is always true.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Fourth Commandment:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Always change at least one argument while recurring. It must be changed to be closer to termination. The changing argument must be tested in the terminating condition: when using cdr, test termination with null?&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 83,</p>

<blockquote><p>Because all *-functions work on lists that are either:
  -empty
  -an atom consed onto a list, or
  -a list consed onto a list</p></blockquote>

<p>Recursive way of looking at short-circuting, pg 88</p>

<blockquote><p>Question: Do you remember what (or &hellip;) does?
Anaser: (or &hellip;) asks questions one at a time until it finds one that is true. Then (or&hellip;) stops, makeing its value true. If it cannot find a true argument, the value of (or &hellip;) is false
And the opposite for (and &hellip;)</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 91, Sixth Commandment</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;But then the  says: "Simplify only after the function is correct&rdquo;, so I shouldn&rsquo;t have skipped to the next iteration, and should have done the first version first because its easier to verify"</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 98</p>

<blockquote><p>Why is (n + 3) a good representation?
Because
1. (n + 3) is an S-expresssion. It can therefore serve as an argument for a function.
2. It structurally resembles n + 3</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 107, Eight Commandment</p>

<blockquote><p>Use help functions to abstract from representations</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 107</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Numbers are representations? Yes. For example 4 stands for the concept four. We chose that symbol because we are accustomed to arabic representations.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 127</p>

<blockquote><p>What kind of values can functions return? Lists and atoms (and functions)
Lambdas (currying) were discovered by Moses Schonfinkel and Haskell B Curry</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 150</p>

<blockquote><p>Can you guess what sorn stands for? Nope. Symbol or Number
Unnatural Recursion, does not recur on a part of lat (but on a result of a passed around function)</p></blockquote>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t collect a lot of quotes from the last 3 chapters (collectors, Y-Comb, intepreter), but here are some of my notes:</p>

<blockquote><p>Really very mind expanding, chapter 9 and 10 are brutal. I thought 8 was hard with collectors but I got that in 2 reads. 9 I&rsquo;ve already read twice and it still blows my mind.
Wow this book is going to break my brain, really cool. Using tables for stack frames and language (identifiers to primitivies/values)
(Stack overflow) Long story short, it allows you to implement recursion in a language that doesn&rsquo;t necessarily support it natively.</p></blockquote>

<p>Y-combinator steps in my words</p>

<blockquote><p>length loses define, redefine length over and over with eternity as end point (use eternity because you lost length)
remove repetitions with create mk-length that creates length-like function
don&rsquo;t need eternity because you never reach it
pass mk-length to itself so it never runs out, but isn&rsquo;t infinite because of base case
make mk-length mk-length into a lambda that returns a function, so you can abstract it out and separate it from length</p></blockquote>

<p>(action)
Look through chapters 8-10 for some quotes</p>

<p>Learning more, recommends:</p>

<blockquote><p>Polya, George. How to Solve it</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commandline Shenanigans]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/07/shenanigans/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-07T14:57:53-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/07/shenanigans</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Table of Contents</h3>

<p>Test</p>

<!-- more -->



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commandline Shenanigans]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/07/commandline-shenanigans/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-07T14:57:53-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/07/commandline-shenanigans</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Table of Contents</h3>

<p><img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/commandline_post/tmux_solarized_dark_profile.png" title="'tmux_solarized_dark_profile.png'" ></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="#artofthecommandline">Art of the Command Line</a></li>
<li><a href="#masteringvim">Mastering Vim</a></li>
<li><a href="#tmux">Tmux</a></li>
<li><a href="#profiles">Profiles</a></li>
<li><a href="#onelinerforkillingapplications">One-liner for Killing Applications</a></li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<p><a name="artofthecommandline"></a></p>

<h3>Art of the Command Line</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always been interested in learning the Command Line better. So I was pretty excited to find this guide on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/">Hacker News</a>, or was it <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/">r/programming</a>? <a href="https://github.com/jlevy/the-art-of-command-line">The Art of the CommandLine</a> by <a href="https://github.com/jlevy">jlevy</a> works as an overview of the most useful things, giving a short introduction so you know what&rsquo;s what. You can then look more into the things using &lsquo;man&rsquo; or a quick google search.</p>

<p>It was a fantastic review of the stuff I knew and introduced me to lots of new tools. Here&rsquo;s a portion of my raw notes on things that were relatively new to me:</p>

<ul>
<li>Everyday Use:

<ul>
<li>xargs (example makes no sense)</li>
<li>HERE document (code block that io redirects list to a command)</li>
<li>mosh (ssh type thing using udp)</li>
<li>percol/fzf (interactive selection of values from output of another command)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Processing Files and Data:

<ul>
<li>uniq (uniq reports or filters out repeated lines in a file, these would be perfect for lucky times)</li>
<li>cut/paste/join, pretty intuitive names but never used or seen these used before</li>
<li>awk/sed, awk is a pattern directed scanning and processing language, sed is a stream editor</li>
<li>repren, for complex renames</li>
<li>rysnc, versatile and fast file copying tools</li>
<li>shuf, shuffle or select random names</li>
<li>patch, works with diff to be the standard for patching source code</li>
<li>hd/hexdump/xxd/bvi/biew/strings+grep/xdelta3 for binary files&hellip;</li>
<li>iconv, convert text encodings</li>
<li>split/csplit to split by size or pattern</li>
<li>zless, zmore, zcat, zgrep to operate on compressed files</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Cool things:

<ul>
<li>Press ctrl-r repeatedly to cycle through more matches,&hellip; or hit the right arrow to put the result in the current -line</li>
<li>ctrl-a, #, enter //enters command as comment so you can go back and edit it later</li>
<li>Brace expansion using {&hellip;}, cp somefile{,.bak} (which expands to cp somefile somefile.bak)</li>
<li>The output of a command can be treated like a file via &lt;(some command). ie, vim &lt;(env)</li>
<li>man ascii</li>
<li>tmux/screen to multiplex the screen (byobu to enhance tmux, dtach for session persistence)</li>
<li>fpp (pathpicker) looks incredibly useful</li>
<li>Tab literal, ctrl-v [Tab] or write $&lsquo;\t&rsquo; (the latter is better as you can copy/paste it)</li>
<li>OSX: &ldquo;Use Option as Meta key&rdquo;. To enable the Option key in Mac OS Terminal as an alt key (such as used in the commands above like alt-b, alt-f, etc.). Does wonders for emacs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>After going through this I decided to dive deeper into:</p>

<ul>
<li>xargs</li>
<li>grep</li>
<li>vim</li>
<li>tmux/dtach (although I wasn&rsquo;t happy with dtach and use tmuxinator instead)</li>
<li>zsh</li>
<li>Profiles (terminal, bash, key remapping, etc)</li>
<li>Cleaning up my environment (ex: had brew and macports fighting with eachother)</li>
</ul>


<p><a name="masteringvim"></a></p>

<h3>Mastering Vim</h3>

<p>Vim needs no introduction. I used vim a lot during university, but just got by rather than pushing the boundaries of what it can actually do. Yes I do love sublime text and neat things it can do like multiple cursors. But vim is incredible, and there is a reason people have been using it for decades.</p>

<p>Inspired by The Art of the CommandLine, I found this went searching for a Vim Guide and found <a href="https://danielmiessler.com/study/vim/">Mastering Vim by Daniel Miessler</a>.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a portion of my notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>u and U interaction is unintuitive to me</li>
<li>CTRL+G, line number+G</li>
<li>CTRL-O, CTRL-I</li>
<li>%</li>
<li>:#,#s/old/new/g</li>
<li>:%s/old/new/g</li>
<li>:%s/old/new/gc</li>
<li>:!</li>
<li>:set ic hls is</li>
<li>:set incsearch</li>
<li>:set noic</li>
<li>:nohlsearch</li>
<li>/ignore\c</li>
<li>:e (followed by CTRL+D)</li>
<li>CTRL+L for redraw</li>
<li>CTRL+[ for ESC</li>
<li>CTRL+E for scroll up</li>
<li>CTRL+Y for scroll down</li>
<li>zz, zt, zb for scroll</li>
</ul>


<p>To practice I went through vimtutor and played <a href="http://vim-adventures.com/">vim adventures</a>. Now I&rsquo;m making a Javascript game with the Phaser framework that will make use of vim commands for controls</p>

<p><a name="tmux"></a></p>

<h3>Tmux</h3>

<p>&ldquo;<a href="https://tmux.github.io/">tmux</a> is a "terminal multiplexer&rdquo;, it enables a number of terminals (or windows) to be accessed and controlled from a single terminal. tmux is intended to be a simple, modern, BSD-licensed alternative to programs such as GNU screen."</p>

<p>Tmux would have been an absolute lifesaver when I was back in school as I did a lot of my work by sshing into the school servers. It would have allowed me to login once and create multiple panes/windows instead of having to login multiple times. So many regrets. It has been instrumental for sshing in and working with my raspberry pi though.</p>

<p>First thing I did was change to prefix from ctrl+a to ctrl+b. The prefix is what you use before entering tmux commands. ctrl+a was originally saved for screen (since the creator of tmux used screen while developing tmux). However, ctrl+a is much easier on your fingers than ctrl+a.</p>

<p>The Art of the CommandLine recommended dtach for session persistence, but I found the redraw to be very buggy. So I looked around and found <a href="https://github.com/tmuxinator/tmuxinator">Tmuxinator</a>, which gas worked perfectly!</p>

<p><a name="profiles"></a></p>

<h3>Profiles</h3>

<p>You can find most of my <a href="https://github.com/nmlau/profiles">Profiles</a> here. This allows them to be cloned in and set up quickly and conveniently. It also allows me to keep track of them in one place. Since hitting &lsquo;ls -al&rsquo; in ~/ is kind of messy.</p>

<p>I messed around with my profiles and environment:</p>

<ul>
<li>Setup <a href="http://www.zsh.org/">zsh</a> and <a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh">Oh My Zsh</a></li>
<li>Installed <a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">Solarized Dark theme</a> for terminal</li>
<li>Changed to <a href="https://www.iterm2.com/">iTerm2</a></li>
<li>Remapped keys: caps to control, remapping vims &lsquo;jk&rsquo; to escape</li>
<li>Fixed up <a href="http://brew.sh/">Homebrew</a> by getting rid of macports, fixing permissions, etc (lots of running &lsquo;brew doctor&rsquo;)</li>
<li>Changed host/terminal name</li>
<li>etc</li>
</ul>


<p><a name="onelinerforkillingapplications"></a></p>

<h3>One-liner for Killing Applications</h3>

<p>Art of the Command Line brought up these:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>ps -ax <span class="p">|</span> grep Finder
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">kill</span> -9 390
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>And I had run into this command: kill <code>jobs -ps</code>, when messing around with background processes</p>

<p>At the same time, I&rsquo;ve always been frustrated by how much time it takes to start up Activity Monitor, search for the offending process, and then clicking multiple times to force quit it. And I&rsquo;ve always got a terminal open so why not just use that and get it done with no waiting, few key presses, and zero clicks. So I looked back at these commands which were pretty close already. I figured I&rsquo;d learn some bash and try to combine them into a one liner that I could throw into an alias for my .zshrc.</p>

<p>I started with this, it read from jobs. And awk would pass the process id column to xargs which would call &lsquo;kill&rsquo; on them</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>zsh: <span class="nb">jobs</span> -p <span class="p">|</span> awk <span class="s1">&#39;{print $3}&#39;</span> <span class="p">|</span> xargs <span class="nb">kill</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>But jobs obviously wasn&rsquo;t right, we wanted &lsquo;ps -ax&rsquo; and to use grep to target the offending app. As well as &lsquo;kill -9&rsquo; to forcequit.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>ps -ax <span class="p">|</span> grep Finder <span class="p">|</span> awk <span class="s1">&#39;{print $3}&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>ps -ax <span class="p">|</span> grep <span class="s1">&#39;TextEdit&#39;</span> <span class="p">|</span> awk <span class="s1">&#39;{print $1}&#39;</span> <span class="p">|</span> xargs <span class="nb">kill</span> -9
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Now there was the issue of passing in the app name as a variable, which requires a <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/941338/how-to-pass-command-line-arguments-to-a-shell-alias">bash function</a>.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nb">alias </span><span class="nv">killapp</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">&#39;function _killapp(){ps -ax | grep $1 | awk &#39;</span><span class="o">{</span>print <span class="nv">$1</span><span class="o">}</span><span class="s1">&#39; | xargs kill -9};_killapp&#39;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>However, now the the grep $1 and awk $1 interfere with eachother. You can pass grep directly to xargs, &lsquo;&hellip; grep $1 | xargs kill -9&rsquo;&hellip; but that&rsquo;s not ideal. I tried a few things, like using a variable. As well as a variety of backslashes and <a href="http://superuser.com/questions/114798/is-there-a-way-to-escape-single-quotes-in-the-shell">quotes around quotes</a></p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nb">alias </span><span class="nv">killapptest</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">&#39;function _killapp(){arg1=&quot;$1&quot;; ps -ax | grep $arg1 | awk &quot;{print $1}&quot;;_killapp&#39;</span> //using variable
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Eventually I found the way that worked, by <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7244534/using-awk-in-bash-alias-or-function">escaping the $</a>:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>* <span class="nb">alias </span><span class="nv">killapp</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">&#39;function _killapp(){ps -ax | grep $1 | awk &quot;{print \$1}&quot; | xargs kill -9};_killapp&#39;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>But not perfect, since grep would find itself. To solve this I found this <a href="http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/74185/how-can-i-prevent-grep-from-showing-up-in-ps-results">stackoverflow thread</a> which recommended:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>pgrep or <span class="s1">&#39;ps aux | grep -v grep | grep &quot;fnord&quot;&#39;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Looking more into pgrep, I remembered seeing it along with pkill in the Art of the Command Line under <a href="https://github.com/jlevy/the-art-of-command-line#everyday-use">Everyday Use</a>. And so with some frustration, to quote myself at that moment:</p>

<blockquote><p>WELL LOOKS LIKE I JUST REINVENTED PGREP/PKILL, THERE GOES AN HOUR AND SOME PRIDE. WELL I GUESS I LEARNED SOMETHING AT LEAST</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mindfulness in Plain English by Henepola Gunaratana]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/04/mindfulness-in-plan-english/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-04T12:51:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2016/01/04/mindfulness-in-plan-english</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Under Construction</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always been interested in meditation. Having grown up in the Silicon Valley, I&rsquo;ve found that the heart of the tech world has an ironic obsession with spirituality. While not busy mining the finest 1&rsquo;s and 0&rsquo;s from the Silcion Valley Mines, idols like Steve Jobs were well known for their obsession with spirituality.</p>

<p>About a year or two ago I began to read more about meditation and started integrating a basic form of deep breathing into my life. After backpacking around Southeast and East Asia for a few months this amateur interest gained steam. Theravada Buddhism is very popular in Southeast Asia, so during my month in Vietnam I had lots of exposure to it while visiting shrines or hanging out with natives. Zen Buddhism is more poplular in East Asia, which matches my ethnicity (I&rsquo;m half Chinese and half Japanese).</p>

<p>After reading around online and practicing the basics I found - r/meditation is a fantastic resource! I decided I wanted to dive depper into the Theravada school of Buddhism. This was because it was more based on the scriptures and thus can be self-studied while Zen tends to need a mentor or teacher to guide you. Thus, I decided to read Mindfulness in Plain English, a well known and practical book on Theravada meditation.</p>

<p>Here are some of my favorite quotes from Mindfulness in Plain English by Henepola Gunaratana. These first four are actually ideas that I keep onhand and reread on a weekly basis.</p>

<p>pg 8</p>

<blockquote><p>Cool ideas in how you grasp at the happy 10%, reject the sad 10% and ignore the neutral 80% (Retrieve actual Quote from book)</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 29 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;That initial perception will spark pleasant, unpleasant or neutral feelings. That is a universal phenomenon. It occurs in the mind of others just as it does in his, and he should see that clearly. Following these feelings various reactions may arise. He may feel greed, lust, or jealousy. He may feel fear, worry, restlessness or boredom. These reactions are universal. He simple notes them and then generalizes. He should realize that these reactions are normal human responses and can arise in anybody.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 11</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Like the breath, mental states have three stages: beginning, middle, and end. Often when you realize your concentration has drifted and you&rsquo;ve been thinking awhile&hellip; it&rsquo;s cause the mental state is near its end. You have to learn to find it at the beginning (as it rises out of your unconscious) and gently watch it through to its end.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>More from Chapter 11</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;We are constantly conceptualizing, to solve our problems, to communicate. But with mindfulness you examine before conceptualization, and look at the pure nature of mental phenomena.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>And many more to follow below!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I have a friend who&rsquo;s an actor LA, this quote reminded me of my conversations of him. As well as showing a practial application of mindfulness - that you can change who you are with it. pg 25</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Tantric&hellip; The self-concept or ego is nothing more than a set of reactions and mental images that are artificially pasted to the flowing process of pure awareness&hellip; The student is given a particular religious image to meditate upon, for examle, one of the deities from the tantric pantheon&hellip;. She takes off her own identity and puts on another. During the process, she is able to watch the way in which the ego is constructed and put in place. She comes to recognize the arbitrary nature of all egos, including her own, and she excapes from bondage to the ego. She is left in a state where she may have an ego if she so chosses - either her own or whichever other she might wish - or she can make do without one&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 25,</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The object of vipassana practice is to learn to see the truths of impermanence, unsatisfactoriness, and selflessness of phenomena. We think we are doing this already, but that is an illusion. It comes from the fact that we are paying so little attention to the ongoing surge of our own life experiences that we might just as well be asleep. We are simply not paying enough attention to nootice that we are not paying attention. It is another Catch-22&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 27 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;10. Don&rsquo;t ponder: You don&rsquo;t need to figure everything out. Discursive thinking won&rsquo;t free you from the trap. In mediation, the mind is purified naturally by mindfulness, by wordless bare attention. Habitual deliberation is not necessary to eliminate those things that are keeping you in bondage. All that is necessary is a clear, non-conceptual perception of what they are and how they work. That alone is sufficient to dissolve them. Concepts and reasoning just get in the way. Don&rsquo;t think. See.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 29 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;When the meditator perceives any sensory object, he is not to dwell upon it in the ordinary egotistical way. He should rather examine the very process of perception itself. He should watch the feelings that arise and the mental activities that follow. He should note the changes that occur in his own consciousness as a result. In watching all these phenomena, the meditator must be aware of the universality of what he is seeing. That initial perception will spark pleasant, unpleasant or neutral feelings. That is a universal phenomenon. It occurs in the mind of others just as it does in his, and he should see that clearly. Following these feelings various reactions may arise. He may feel greed, lust, or jealousy. He may feel fear, worry, restlessness or boredom. These reactions are universal. He simple notes them and then generalizes. He should realize that these reactions are normal human responses and can arise in anybody.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 29 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;At that point, without trying to confuse the feeling with the mental formations, we should isolate the feeling as feeling and watch it mindfully. Feeling is one of the seven universal mental factors. The other six are contact, perception, mental formations, concentration, life force, and awareness.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 34 (pdf)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;d) The fourth method is to take a long breath. When the lungs are full, mentally count "one&rdquo; and breath out completely until the lungs are empty of fresh air. Then count mentally &ldquo;two&rdquo;. Take a long breath again and count &ldquo;three&rdquo; and breathe completely out as before. When the lungs are empty of fresh air, count mentally &ldquo;four&rdquo;. Count your breath in this manner up to ten. Then count backward from ten to one. Count again from one to ten and then ten to one."</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 5</p>

<blockquote><p>The practice: Start with Empathy and loving kindness, Three deep breaths to concentrate, then tip of nostrils, then find your sign</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 93</p>

<blockquote><p>Pain is inevitable, suffering is not</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 10 on dealing with problems</p>

<blockquote><p>Blissful feeling or sense of failure are actually drawing you away from mindfulness</p></blockquote>

<p>pg 113</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Thoughts of greed cover everything connected with desire, from outright avarice for material gain, all the way down to a subtle need to be respected as a moral person. Thoughts of hatred run the gamut from petty peevishness to murderous rage. Delusion covers everything from daydreaming through actual hallucinations. Generosity cancels greed. Benevolence and compassion cancel hatred. You can find a specific antidote for any troubling thought if you just think about it a while.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 11, dealing with distractions 2</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Temporarily meditate on distractions. Wordlessly answer these questions: what is it, how strong is it, how long does it last&rdquo;
&ldquo;Like the breath, mental states have three stages: beginning, middle, and end. Often when you realize you&rsquo;re concentration has drifted and you&rsquo;ve been thinking awhile&hellip; it&rsquo;s cause the mental state is near its end. You have to learn to find it at the beginning (as it rises out of your unconscious) and gently watch it through to its end&rdquo;
&ldquo;We are constantly conceptualizing, to solve our problems, to communicate. But with mindfulness you examine before conceptualization, and look at the pure nature of mental phenomena&rdquo;
&ldquo;Realize that you have been off the track for such and such a length of time and go back to the breath. There is no need for any negative reaction at all. The very act of realizing that you have been off the track is an active awareness. It is an exercise of pure mindfulness all by itself.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Chapter 14, Mindfulness vs Concentration</p>

<blockquote><p>A distinction that I hadn&rsquo;t realized:
Mindfulness is more important overall, but concentration is what you have to focus on in the begininng. Or else monkey mind will overwhelm mindfulness with random chatter. Overall, mindfulness will lead to better concentration by making you aware that your concentration has slipped and allowing you to re-engage it</p></blockquote>

<p>The Power of Loving Friendliness, The Four Sublime States</p>

<blockquote><p>Loving Friendliness, Compassion, Appreciative Joy, and Equanimity
Uses the metaphor of having a child. Before the child is born, it&rsquo;s already being cared for regardless of its actions. This is metta or loving friendliness. As the infant starts exploring the world, it will hurt itself sometimes, and the parents feel the same pain. This is compassion. When the child gets older and goes to school, it will have successes, and the parents will feel happiness for it. This is appreciative joy. Finally, when the child goes out on his own,  the parents will practice equanimity: the appreciate that they have done all they could for the child but no longer steer the outcome of the child&rsquo;s life</p></blockquote>

<p>Appendix: the Context of the Tradition</p>

<blockquote><p>Vipassana is &ldquo;insight&rdquo;, a clear awareness of exactly what is happening as it happens
Samatha can be translated as &ldquo;concentration&rdquo; or &ldquo;tranquillity,&rdquo; and is a state in which the mind is focused only on one item, brought to rest, and not allowed to wander"
This book focuses on Theravada Buddhishm, common in South and Southeast Asia. The other main school is Mahaya Buddhism which is more common in East Asia, mainly the Zen school. A quick google search shows that Theravada is better for my situation, although it doesn&rsquo;t line up with my heritage. The reasons for this is that it is more based on scriptures so less based on teacher</p></blockquote>

<p>As a disclaimer: I&rsquo;m not a big fan of the intro, it is very preachy. Promising the solution to all lifes problems and happiness, blah blah. I feel like I&rsquo;m being sold snake oil. It mocks normal people and the way they live&hellip; for example, page 8. I HATE THIS PARAGRAPH, civilization is responsible for so much good. Technology has raised our standard of living insanely. And no people are not trying to steal my watch.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Wait a minute, though. Peace and happiness! Isn&rsquo;t that what civilization is all about? We build skyscrapers and freeways. We have paid vacations, TV sets. We provide free hospitals and sick leaves, Social Security and welfare benefits. All of that is aimed at providing some measure of peace and happiness. Yet the rate of mental illness climbs steadily, and the crime rates rise faster. The streets are crawling with delinquents and unstable individuals. Stick your arms outside the safety of your own door and somebody is very likely to steal your watch! Something is not working. A happy man does not feel driven to kill. We like to think that our society is exploiting every area of human knowledge in order to achieve peace and happiness.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MyFitnessJourney]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/18/myfitnessjourney/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-18T06:37:41-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/18/myfitnessjourney</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Under Construction</h1>

<h3>Introduction</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ll start with a disclaimer: This isn&rsquo;t a guide. This is <em>my</em> fitness journey, how I achieved <em>my</em> goals with the time and effort <em>I</em> was willing to put forth. Although, at the same time, I&rsquo;m a pretty normal guy so maybe these things will apply to you as well. Also, friends will often ask for advice so I figure I can just direct them here rather than attempt to cover everything poorly in person, and have them not retain that much.</p>

<p>This whole post could be summed up with: Eat, Sleep, Workout, Be Consistent</p>

<h3>Table of Contents</h3>

<ul>
<li>Background</li>
<li>What I used to do</li>
<li>Transition to Power Lifting</li>
<li>Studying</li>
<li>Nutrition, Lifting, Sleep, <em>Sustainability</em></li>
<li>Cutting</li>
<li>Bulking</li>
<li>Progress Pics and Body Scan results</li>
<li>Favorite Resources</li>
</ul>


<h3>Background</h3>

<p>Since June I&rsquo;ve gone from 139 lbs to 143 lbs. From:</p>

<ul>
<li>67.2 lbs of Skeletal Muscle Mass, 21.2 lbs of Body Fat Mass, with a 15.1 Body Fat percentage</li>
<li>72.3 lbs of Skeletal Muscle Mass, 16.3 lbs of Body Fat Mass, with a 11.4 Body Fat percentage</li>
</ul>


<p>Here&rsquo;s some of my lifts, I&rsquo;ve mostly moved into intermediate going on proficient territory. So I&rsquo;m pretty happy but I&rsquo;ve got a long ways to go:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th> <strong>Lift</strong>          </th>
<th> <strong>5 Rep Max (lbs)</strong> </th>
<th> <strong>Theoretical 1 Rep (lbs)</strong> </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> Back Squat        </td>
<td> 240                 </td>
<td> 280                      </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Deadlift          </td>
<td> 240                 </td>
<td> 280                      </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Bench Press       </td>
<td> 185                 </td>
<td> 225                      </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Overhead Press    </td>
<td> 115                 </td>
<td> 135                      </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Weighted Pull-up  </td>
<td> 45                  </td>
<td> 75                       </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Pendlay Row       </td>
<td> 135                 </td>
<td> 155                      </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<!-- more -->


<h3>What I used to Do</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always been casually interested in fitness. I was raised on sports, and have played the majority of sports with my friends at some point. From rugby, wrestling, wiffleball, ping pong, etc. I ran track and cross country in highschool which got me a free member ship to the gym. So I would jog over to the local gym and work out on the machines, religiously following the given Range of Motion. I would do sets of 75 ten pound dumbbell curls, pushups to feel more productive while watching the sharks or warriors play.</p>

<p>During university, I would find routines off the internet, often combining them into some strange amalgamation based on what I thought was best. I would drink whey protein, and make mediocre progress until midterms or finals came by and then start all over again. Overall, I saw little progress over the course of 4 years.</p>

<h3>Transition to Power Lifting</h3>

<p>Then I discovered power lifting. This by itself wasn&rsquo;t the most important thing, that was the resources it lead me too. But we&rsquo;ll get to that later. I picked up the beginner powerlifing routine Stronglifts 5x5s. Yes, I was still a beginner after 4 years. This routine forced me to pick up a bunch of important lifts that I had been neglecting or had been too afraid to try, such as Squats, Deadlifts, and Overhead Press. It made them easy to pick up by starting the weights very low. It provided things beyond lifts and reps, such as when to deload.</p>

<h3>Studying</h3>

<h3>Nutrition, Lifting, Sleep, <em>Sustainability</em></h3>

<h3>Cutting</h3>

<h3>Bulking</h3>

<h3>Progress Pics and Body Scan results</h3>

<h3>Favorite Resources</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://examine.com/">Examine</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fitness">r/fitness</a></li>
<li><a href="http://symmetricstrength.com/">Symmetric Strength</a></li>
<li><a href="http://iifym.com/iifym-calculator/">iifym</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Javascript]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/07/learning-javascript/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-07T15:22:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/07/learning-javascript</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Under Construction</h2>

<h3>Table of Contents</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#mdnreintroduction">MDN Reintroduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#crockfordonjavascript">Crockford on JavaScript</a></li>
<li><a href="#mdngamedevelopment">MDN Game Development Workflows</a></li>
<li><a href="#buildingagame">Building a Game</a></li>
</ul>


<p><a name="introduction"></a></p>

<h3>Introduction</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always been interested in learning Javascript, but have been too overwhelmed by the abundance of resources out there. I finally took the time to do some thorough looking around with lead me to this Stack Overflow <a href="http://goo.gl/iPMGV">link</a> on resources for learning Javascript. This lead me to the MDN Javascript Reintroduction and Crockfords Lectures.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><a name="mdnreintroduction"></a></p>

<h3>MDN Reintroduction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/A_re-introduction_to_JavaScript">Mozilla Developer Network (MDN) Reintroduction to JavaScript</a></li>
<li><a href="http://beej.us/blog/data/javascript-prototypes-inheritance/">Beej Guide: JavaScript Prototypes and Inheritance</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Learning javascript made me realize how little I knew about the languages I was comfortable with. Programming in my comfort languages (Java/C++) had become almost like being fluent in English, I forgot a many of the little details and rules here and there.</p>

<p>It was a good dose of reality to get me out of my comfort zone and push me to learn the deeper details of languages.</p>

<p><a name="crockfordonjavascript"></a></p>

<h3>Crockford on JavaScript</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxAXlJEmNMg">Volume 1: The Early Years</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RO1Wnu-xKoY">Chapter 2: And Then There Was JavaScript</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ya4UHuXNygM">Act III: Function the Ultimate</a>

<ul>
<li>This talk also convinced me to pick up Little Schemer, promising that it would &ldquo;change the way you think, and there aren&rsquo;t a lot of books that will do that&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fv9qT9joc0M">Episode IV: The Matamorphasis of Ajax</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=47Ceot8yqeI">Part 5: The End of All Things</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QgwSUtYSUqA">Scene 6: Loopage</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UTEqr0IlFKY">Level 7: ECMAScript 5: The new Parts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=taaEzHI9xyY">Section 8: Programming Style &amp; Your Brain</a></li>
</ul>


<p>The first two talks are a history lesson, very informative. A lot of the languages and software architects have come up in random reading around the internet, such as some of my favorite (research) papers:</p>

<ul>
<li>Ken Thompson&rsquo;s Turing Award Lecture, &ldquo;Reflections on Trusting Trust&rdquo;</li>
<li>Lamport&rsquo;s &ldquo;The Future of Computing: Logic or Biology&rdquo;</li>
<li>CAR Hoare, &ldquo;The Emperor&rsquo;s Old Clothes&rdquo;</li>
<li>Fred Brooks (1986), &ldquo;No Silver Bullet&rdquo;</li>
<li>Parnas, David L. “Designing Software for Ease of Extension and Contraction.”</li>
</ul>


<p>I really enjoyed the foundations of JavaScript. How Netscape had Brendan Eich create a web language. He wanted to base it on Scheme, but Netscape put its foot down and said they wanted it to be more approachable. So Eich used the syntax of JavaScript, the first-class functions of Scheme, and the Prototype Chain of Self to make one of the most popular languages of all time. And in 4 weeks! Although this short time frame is responsible for a lot of JavaScript&rsquo;s blunders which are slowly being repaired (ES6 Strict was a big jump).</p>

<p>Some benefits of Prototyped OOP:</p>

<ul>
<li>Trivial to make new &ldquo;classes&rdquo;, avoids lots of boilerplate</li>
<li>More &ldquo;functional&rdquo; style</li>
<li>Change behavior at runtime</li>
<li>Easy multiple inheritance, don&rsquo;t need crazy and hard to maintain type hierarchy</li>
<li>Property modifiers</li>
</ul>


<p>Wouldn&rsquo;t be complete without cons list:</p>

<ul>
<li>Lose static typing</li>
<li>Performance overhead, still have to check inheritance hierarchy and compiler can&rsquo;t help you out</li>
<li>New is scary, can easily accidentally clobber global object</li>
</ul>


<p>Now that I knew a lot of the theory behind Javascript, it was time to practice applying it. I decided to make a game.</p>

<p><a name="mdngamedevelopment"></a></p>

<h3>MDN Game Development Workflows</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Games/Workflows/2D_Breakout_game_pure_JavaScript">2D Breakout in pure JS</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/resources/games/breakout/">Try it!</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Games/Workflows/2D_Breakout_game_Phaser">2D Breakout game using Phaser</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/resources/games/breakoutPhaser/">Try it!</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Games/Workflows/HTML5_Gamedev_Phaser_Device_Orientation">2D Maze game with Device Orientation using Phaser</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/resources/games/phaserMaze/">Try it!</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><a name="buildingagame"></a></p>

<h3>Building a Game</h3>

<p>You can try it out, it is still a work in progress though. It was really fun to not just program this, but design it, create the maps&hellip; to have complete control. I did have several issues developing it though, mostly with JavaScript.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/nmlau/vim-maze">My Game</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/resources/games/vimMaze/">Try it!</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>List of issues and what I learned:</p>

<ul>
<li>Hosting issues: browser was caching objects so when I updated and went to test my changes&hellip; everything would be the same. Octopress had some issues with actually changing letter capitalization in the repo that prevented a few scripts from loading properly.</li>
<li>Maps: used Tile Map Editor to generate json maps.</li>
<li>Pass in method, not method call as callback. If you pass the method call then it will only get called once AND have the wrong context.</li>
<li>Make sure to pass the context. &lsquo;this&rsquo; isn&rsquo;t passed around implicitly like in java, context is generally one part of a long list of arguments.</li>
<li>Using an unfamiliar framework in a new language was difficult. While Java does have varargs, the way Javascript parameters work was still weird, like how you could leave them out and wouldn&rsquo;t even get a warning. Even with the docs open, a lot of the high level functions had huge lists of parameters and I would often misread, misunderstand, or forget something.</li>
<li>Modularizing. Awkward in Phaser, it doesn&rsquo;t provide a built in way to do it. This is because sites like to have games in a single minified js file. Being used to OOPs highly structured and separated classes this was kind of weird. But hey, this is what you learn new technologies and languages for.</li>
<li>Debugging. The console has awesome debugger tools built in. Just throw the &lsquo;debugger&rsquo; statement into your Javascript code. I make sure to use the &lsquo;.js&rsquo; library rather than &lsquo;min.js&rsquo; so I can use the debugger to source code dive.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favorite Tools and Tricks]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/03/favorite-tools-and-tricks/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-03T00:26:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/03/favorite-tools-and-tricks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was showing two of my engineer buddies something on my laptop when I realized they didn&rsquo;t know how to shortcut between tabs. It blew my mind that people don&rsquo;t know these things, which got my thinking about all the little tips and tricks I&rsquo;ve picked up over the years. I ended up making a list&hellip; so I figured I might as well share it. I&rsquo;ll throw on a quick summary for why I use all these things. For example:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Google</em>, Really really good search engine. A strong alternative to Bing if you&rsquo;re willing to give up the $125/year that Microsoft will give you for clicks.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ve mostly found these through annoyance at minor inconveniences, whether they be multiple keystrokes or the laborious task of moving my hands to the keyboard and back.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Chrome Shortcuts</h3>

<ul>
<li>Remove item from search bar and history, opt+cmd+del</li>
<li>Switching between tabs, shift+opt+{} or ctrl+shift+tab</li>
<li>Jumping between tabs, cmd+(0-9)</li>
<li>Moving to address bar, cmd+L</li>
</ul>


<h3>Gmail Shortcuts (have to enable them)</h3>

<ul>
<li>Refresh inbox, u</li>
<li>Move between messages, j/k</li>
<li>Archive and Move between messages, {/}</li>
<li>Move to search bar, /</li>
<li>Open message, o</li>
<li>Move between Folders, g+(i for inbox)(t for sent)(l for label)(s for starred)(a for all)</li>
<li>Compose, c</li>
<li>Send, cmd+enter</li>
</ul>


<h3>Chrome Extensions</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Vimium</em>, I couldn&rsquo;t live without this one. It lets you use chrome with vim inspired shortcuts. Hit &rsquo;d' to go down half a page, &lsquo;k&rsquo; to scroll up, &lsquo;gi&rsquo; to move cursor to a textarea then &lsquo;tab&rsquo; to move to the next textarea, etc.</li>
<li><em>Papaly</em>, I have two tabs pinned&hellip; gmail and papaly. Papaly lets me save links in a quick and organized manner, letting me keep my browser uncluttered.</li>
<li><em>Empty New Tab Page</em>, Because it cleans up your interface ever so slightly, &ldquo;a clean room is a clean mind&rdquo;.</li>
<li><em>Imagus</em>, hover to see full size image. Have it configured to show image on shift press.</li>
<li><em>goo.gl URL Shortener</em>, this is very particular to my workflow. Whenever I find something valuable on the internet, I&rsquo;ll throw a quick summary and it&rsquo;s goog.gl link on a plain text to review later.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Privacy</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Ghostery</em>, Ghostery blocks 3rd party trackers, make sure to disable GhostRank.</li>
<li><em>TrackMeNot</em>, clicks every ad (but doesn&rsquo;t load them) to obfuscate your actual activity.</li>
<li><em>uBlockOrigin</em>, uBlockOrigin, largely superior Adblock Plus. More efficient.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Software</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Flux</em>, reduces eyestrain by adapting your computer screen to the time of day. Takes some adjusting to. But after that you won&rsquo;t be able to live without it.</li>
<li><em>Moom</em>, window management, lets me move my windows anywhere I want with an efficient hotkey. Mandatory if you&rsquo;re working with larger monitors (I have a 27" and 24").</li>
<li><em>VPN</em>, lets me feel safe when I&rsquo;m on public wifi. Was especially useful when I backed around Asia. I personally use Private Internet Access (PIA), one of the bigger providers.</li>
<li><em>Copy Clip</em>, clipboard manager for os x. It&rsquo;s free, why not?</li>
<li><em>Google Spreadsheets</em>, have several of these setup for subjects that require more organization. Is conveniently synced between phone and computers.</li>
<li><em>Pomodoro Timer</em>, more for my workflow. I work on tasks in 30 minute chunks so its perfect.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Knowledge base</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Sublime Text</em>, have it opened with entire Dropbox directory. cmd+shift+f executes an interactive grep-like search, makes it very easy to find what I&rsquo;m looking for. cmd+t lets me quickly open whatever file I want.</li>
<li><em>Nebulous for iOS</em>, plain text editor and Dropbox compatibility. Lets me view and edit my knowledge base. Great for my todo lists and to productively kill time when I&rsquo;m waiting in line.</li>
<li><em>Dropbox</em>, keeps everything synced. Although I did have to pay for more storage.</li>
<li><em>Org mode</em>, incredible! Plan to integrate this into workflow shortly.</li>
<li><em>Evernote</em>, you all know what this is. I&rsquo;m not it&rsquo;s biggest fan, eventually I want to move to an org mode + dropbox + sublime/nebulous workflow. But for now, I use its reminders to re-expose me to particularily interesting pieces of knowledge. Huge issues include: inconvenient exporting, no multiple hierachies of notes/notebooks, ads everywhere, general bugginess.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Sublime Text</h3>

<ul>
<li>ctrl+cmd+up/down arrows, swap rows up and down.</li>
<li>ctrl+shift+up/down arrows, quickly spawn multiple cursors for some efficient editing.</li>
<li>cmd+k then cmd+b, hide/show sidebar</li>
<li>ctrl+shift+k, delete the current line your cursor is on</li>
<li>Many many more, but I don&rsquo;t want to go overboard</li>
</ul>


<h3>OS X</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Spotlight</em>, cmd+space. Let&rsquo;s you find anything on your computer quickly and conveniently. Whether it&rsquo;s an application, file, widget.</li>
<li><em>Hot Corners</em>, move the mouse to bottom left or right corner to put my laptop to sleep. Lets me take faster bathroom breaks at the coffee shop.</li>
<li>Remapping Caps to Control at OS level (Modifier Keys). Especially useful for the Command Line Interface. Who uses Caps Lock anyways.</li>
<li>PLEASE NEVER MOVE THROUGH TEXT BY HOLDING THE ARROW KEYS (and try to avoid the mouse). cmd+left/right arrows, move to beginning or end of line. option+left/right arrow, move a word at a time, similar to vim&rsquo;s &lsquo;w&rsquo; and &lsquo;b&rsquo; commands.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Peace of Mind</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Crashplan</em>, backs up my computer to a remote location every night while I&rsquo;m sleeping. I backup with my harddrive weekly for a local backup. So unless the right data center and my house burn down simultaneously I&rsquo;m fine.</li>
<li><em>Mint</em>, free personal budgeting application. I used to constantly worry about whether I was getting mischarged, having my credit cards stolen, or paying fees I shouldn&rsquo;t be. With this I can check every couple days and never have to worry.</li>
<li><em>1Password</em>, just in case I forget. Sync my keychain over dropbox so it&rsquo;s available in case of emergencies.</li>
</ul>


<h3>App Specific</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Mint Mojito</em>, improves ui for mint. You can cut out sections you don&rsquo;t want, like: recommendations, ads, etc&hellip;</li>
<li><em>Google Calendar Scroll Disabler</em>, because the trackpad is way too sensitive and I often found myself a year ahead of where I wanted to be.</li>
<li><em>The Camelizer</em>, tracks Amazon prices. Let&rsquo;s you see if you&rsquo;re getting a good deal or should wait. Can set price watches that will notify you when the price drops to what you&rsquo;re willing to pay. Along this note, using ifttt to watch rss feeds or using slickdeals deal watchers is really effective as well.</li>
<li><em>Reddit Enhancement Suite</em>, I can&rsquo;t remember what it was like to not have this.</li>
<li><em>Download FB Album mod</em>, lets you download albums off Facebook, in case they ever go out of business.</li>
<li><em>Boomerang for Gmail</em>, Lets you program mail to be sent at certain times. Nice when you&rsquo;re doing email at 3am, but want it sent out at a reasonable time.</li>
<li>Facebook: <em>News Feed Blocker</em>, <em>Facebook Unseen</em> (I know this should be in App-Specific&hellip; but for real). When you open facebook to jump on the messenger, the feed is less likely to draw you in&hellip; and unseen so that you can read messages without beening inclined to answer them until it&rsquo;s more convenient. Remember when the &lsquo;seen at 4:21&rsquo; feature was new and everyone despised it?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Alarm]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/01/raspberry-pi-alarm/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-01T16:16:28-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/01/raspberry-pi-alarm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Under Construction</h2>

<h3>Table of Contents</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#components">Components</a></li>
<li><a href="#setup">Setup</a></li>
<li><a href="#programming">Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="#brickwalls">Brickwalls</a></li>
<li><a href="#nextsteps">Next Steps</a></li>
</ul>


<p><a name="introduction"></a></p>

<h3>Introduction</h3>

<p><img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/pi_post/pi.jpg" title="'pi.jpg'" ></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always had trouble waking up. Sometimes I wake up, sometimes I don&rsquo;t, sometimes I just end up lying in bed&hellip; it&rsquo;s been a lifetime point of stress. But in the last few months I&rsquo;ve found a solution that works for me. I use the <a href="http://www.sleepcycle.com/">Sleep Cycle Phone App</a> to gently wake me up so I&rsquo;m ready for my out of bed alarm that goes off at 630 (weekdays) or 830 (weekends). This forces me to get out of bed to walk across the room and turn it off.</p>

<p>But with the larger problem solved, there&rsquo;s always more you can do to make it more perfect. Right now I&rsquo;m using an iPad as my out of bed alarm. There&rsquo;s a lot of problems here: it&rsquo;s a really pricey device being used for a very simple task, it can be inefficient to turn off or adjust alarm times (I don&rsquo;t enjoy the gui), the battery will eventually run out, and if I wake up early there&rsquo;s no kill button to stop my normal alarm from going off without remembering to turn them back on.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a lot of pros though, the battery lasts for several weeks, it doesn&rsquo;t need to be plugged in (I&rsquo;m a little OCD and don&rsquo;t want extra wires).</p>

<p>On top of this, I&rsquo;ve been hearing about Raspberry Pi&rsquo;s for years and have always wanted to mess around with one. This seemed like the perfect project to get started on the DIY journey.</p>

<p>Note: this isn&rsquo;t so much of a guide as my reflections on my journey to solidify the things I learned.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><a name="components"></a></p>

<h3>Components</h3>

<p>How I chose my components, used these two guides: <a href="http://www.howtogeek.com/138281/the-htg-guide-to-getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/all/">Getting Started Guide</a> and <a href="http://www.htpcbeginner.com/raspberry-pi-accessories-for-xbmc-media-center/2/">Component Guide</a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what I bought:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.alliedelec.com/raspberry-pi-raspberry-pi-2-model-b/70465426/">Raspberry Pi 2</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004TA0AUW/">MicroSD Card - Transcend Class 10</a> (preferably preloaded with NOOBS, but it&rsquo;s easy to set it up yourself)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B003MTTJOY">WiFi Adapter - Edimax</a> I got the Edimax rather than the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00EQT0YK2/">Panda 300Mbps</a>, because it has a nano adapter and the Panda is overkill at 300Mbps. Or just use ethernet.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00OY7HR1U">Power Adapter - Northpada</a> Northpada because better reviews, higher mAH, one piece charger. In hindsight, I should have just used one of the many micro USB cables I have sitting around and plugged them into a usb outlet.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00MQLB1N6">Case</a>, although at first I accidentally bought the a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008TCUXLW">Model 1 Case</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Already owned:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Dell-UltraSharp-27-Inch-LED-Lit-Monitor/dp/B00P0EQD1Q">Monitor</a>, any monitor will do. HDMI is more convenient though</li>
<li><a href="http://shop.daskeyboard.com/products/das-keyboard-ultimate-model-s">Keyboard</a>, you can use any usb keyboard, I had a few lying around. Wireless is always convenient too</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003TG75EG">Mouse</a>, and any usb mouse. Wireless always good</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0002L5R78">HDMI Display Cable</a>, Raspberry Pi has a HDMI display port, I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ve got one lying around. Or if your monitor can&rsquo;t do HDMI, use one of the many adapters out there. All modern display cables are digital and can be converted from one to another.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00316263Y">Ethernet</a>, Got hundreds of these too</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00YARCGOC">Speaker</a>, Choose the favorite one you&rsquo;ve got lying around. All you need is a 3.5mm Audio cable to plug it in</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://ozzmaker.com/2013/10/24/how-to-control-the-gpio-on-a-raspberry-pi-with-an-ir-remote/">Hooking up Infrared Remote</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.adafruit.com/products/389">Mini Remote Control (IR)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.adafruit.com/products/157">IR Receiver Sensor</a></li>
<li>Ribbon Cable</li>
<li>Breakout (40 pin)</li>
<li>Breadboard</li>
<li>Wires (3v3 power to IR Out, Ground to IR GND, GPIO 18 - PCM_CLK to IR Vs)</li>
<li>Notes: Might be able to attach IR sensor straight to GPIO. Also, LEDs and most wires are just for testing. Yes, can solder wires straight to GPIO, but that would be permanent. But I could solder wires to breakout and not need the breadboard. Also, don&rsquo;t need LEDs or capacitors for testing, can see input to socket on commandline. Getting all these components was somewhat of a hassle, borrowed parts from a friend but didn&rsquo;t realize he had the old 24 pin breakout/ribbon.</li>
</ul>


<p>Optional:</p>

<ul>
<li>Heatsink, don&rsquo;t think you need this unless I&rsquo;m running HD video constantly. A lot of people, like my dad, use their Pi&rsquo;s as DVRs</li>
</ul>


<p>I ended up doing a headless setup where I ssh&rsquo;d in from my laptop (more on this later). This eliminated the need for: Monitor, Keyboard, Mouse, Display Cable. And switching to ethernet meant no need for a wifi adapter</p>

<p><a name="setup"></a></p>

<h3>Setup</h3>

<ul>
<li>Download Noobs (make sure not copy files in, not the folder)</li>
<li>Download and use formatter, make sure to have lock switch off</li>
<li>Plug everything in</li>
<li>Turn on, Install Raspian</li>
<li>Initial Settings screen: Turn on SSH, expand filesystem</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/forums/viewtopic.php?f=91&amp;t=74176">Setting up headless</a>:
I&rsquo;m a little bit of a neat freak. And I don&rsquo;t have enough space at the moment for a dedicated work bench. So shortly after I went through all the trouble of acquiring and plugging in all the components plugged in I realized I could do better. A headless setup means all the pi needs is an internet connection (wifi adapter or ethernet) and I can use it over ssh.</p>

<p>I got to learn a lot about networking, having to mess around with commands like &lsquo;arp -a&rsquo;, &lsquo;nmap&rsquo;, modifying /etc/ssh/ssh_config, <a href="http://whatismyipaddress.com/mac-address">learn about MAC and ARP addresses</a></p>

<p>Even once I was connected, the workflow was mediocre until I was able to setup:
File Transfer using <a href="http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/8950/copy-files-from-osx-to-from-pi">afp (appletalk protocol) to pi</a>
-Install netatalk on pi, afp in from mac
-This let me use finder and all my os x apps to access my pi&rsquo;s files. Much better than the trouble I was having with Filezilla. Incredibly convenient although it did leave hidden .AppleDouble folders in every directory
Another huge thing was using tmux combined with dtach. Tmux meant I only had to ssh in one time, then I could split that session into several windows. dtach allowed me to shut the pi off, ssh back in jump right back to my desired tmux session.</p>

<p>Random note: sshing in forced me to use command line a lot. Which inspired me to read a few <a href="https://github.com/jlevy/the-art-of-command-line">guides on CLI</a>, <a href="https://danielmiessler.com/study/vim/">vim</a>, that got me play with my profiles (my vim is beautiful now - <a href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/pi_post/tmux_solarized_dark_profile.png">image of Solarized profile with tmux</a>) to setup my profiles like <a href="https://github.com/nmlau/profiles">this</a>. Not to mention finally setting up zsh, more convenient keykindings, etc.</p>

<p><a name="programming"></a></p>

<h3>Programming</h3>

<p>Source available on <a href="https://github.com/nmlau/RPiAlarm">github</a></p>

<p>I got my inspiration from: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=julETnOLkaU">Speaking Alarm Clock</a>, <a href="https://github.com/skiwithpete/alarmpi">github available here</a>. And some better <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/forums/viewtopic.php?f=41&amp;t=95500">Alternative Alarm Clock Projects</a>, most notably the <a href="https://github.com/bubbl/SimpleGoogleAlarmClock">Simple Google Alarm Clock</a></p>

<p>One set the alarm with chronjobs, another by hardcoding, but I really liked the Google Calendar integration. And plan to add some pyfeed stuff, particularily to get weather. I also stole how they used datetime module, config parser, os and mpg123 to play sound files. However, all these projects were deprecated because of changes to the Google Calendar Service API.</p>

<p>One of them suggested setting up a socket to listen for real world events, so I&rsquo;m setting one up to work with an Infrared Remote (IR).</p>

<p>Was actually pretty easy to setup, I was worried since it seemed like there were a lot of places for it to go wrong. I&rsquo;ve never breadboarded before so I was pleasantly surprised by how easy it was. Python and Linux provide easy to use libraries like lirc to decode infrared signals and provide them to a socket. I did have some trouble with mode2 (measures pulse/space length of infarred signals), but was able to troubleshoot that by modifying some .conf files.</p>

<p><a name="brickwalls"></a></p>

<h3>Brickwalls</h3>

<p>Here are some problems that took longer to solve than they should have. In other words, things I learned:</p>

<ul>
<li>Setup was actually the longest part, I had to follow a lot of tutorials that didn&rsquo;t work without going in and understanding the commands better</li>
<li>Changes in Google Calendar API also slowed me down more than they should have. I accidentally setup the deprecated API at first&hellip; wish they had thrown a note on the article that it had been deprcated two years ago!</li>
<li>Just learning python so had some trouble here, easily fixed though. Just read some guides, learned syntax better, got the normal tools like pdb for debugger</li>
<li>Learned how to use a GPIO, got my EE friends to show me how to use a breadboard, ribbon cable, wiring, etc. Closest I had gotten to this stuff before was an FPGA in my embedded systems course or using VHDL to design a CPU although no actual hardware was involved in that.</li>
<li>Time was a huge hassle, I learned a lot about how the time modules worked together, and about formatting. I&rsquo;ll probably swap that all out at some point and just use the arrow module</li>
</ul>


<p><a name="nextsteps"></a></p>

<h3>Next Steps</h3>

<p>You can see in the picture at the top that it is a mess of components. Breadboarding is more of a testing thing, I&rsquo;ll have to learn to solder to get around it. Luckily I have lots of Mechanical Engineering friends. It still won&rsquo;t be organized enough for me though, next it will need a case/enclosing to keep it all in one place and organize the cables it needs (power/ethernet). As to why I want to use ethernet, my home&rsquo;s wifi can be inconsistent and I don&rsquo;t trust it to wake me up.</p>

<p>Power is a huge issue, the iPad I&rsquo;m using for my alarm right now can go for months without being charged. I really like how it doesn&rsquo;t need a wire running to it&hellip; I&rsquo;ll have to look into how I can get a wireless setup for my pi alarm clock. I know they have external battery packs, but can it last as long as the iPad can?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Tale of Two Cities by Charles Dickens]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/10/27/a-tale-of-two-cities-by-charles-dickens/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-27T14:17:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/10/27/a-tale-of-two-cities-by-charles-dickens</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some of my favorite quotes from A Tale of Two Cities by Charles Dickens:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;I should like to ask you: -Does your childhood seem far off? Do the days when you sat at your mother&rsquo;s knee, seem days of very long ago?</p>

<p>Responding to his softened maner, Mr. Lorry answered:</p>

<p>Twenty years back, yes; at this time of my life, no. For, as I draw closer and closer to the end, I travel in the circle, nearer and nearer to the beginning. It seems to be one of the kind smoothings and preparings of the way. My heart is touched now, by many remembrances that had long fallen asleep, of my pretty young mother (and I so old!), and by many associations of the days when what we call the World was not so real with me, and my faults were not confirmed in me."</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<!-- -->


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The wretched wife of the innocent man thus doomed to die, fell under the sentence, as if she had been mortally stricken. But, she uttered no sound; and so strong was the voice within her, representing that it was she of all the world who must uphold him in his misery and not augment it, that it quickly raised her, even from that shock.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meditations by Marcus Aurelius]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/09/12/meditations-by-marcus-aurelius/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-12T13:51:55-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/09/12/meditations-by-marcus-aurelius</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some of my favorite quotes from Meditations by Marcus Aurelius:</p>

<p>Book 6.54</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;That which is not good for the swarm is not good for the bee either.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Book 7.7</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Think not so much of what you lack as of what you have: but of the things that you have, select the best, and then reflect how eagerly you would have sought them if you did not have them. At the same time, however, take care that you do not through being so pleased with them accustom yourself to overvalue them, so as to be disturbed if you should ever not have them.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>Book 8.48</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Remember that the ruling faculty is invincible, when, self-collected, it is satisfied with itself, if it does nothing that it does not choose to do, even if it resists from mere obstinacy. What then will it be when it forms a judgment about anything aided by reason and deliberately? Therefore the mind that is free from passions is a citadel, for man has nothing more secure to which he can fly for refuge and repel every attck. He then who has not seen this is an ignorant man; but he who has seen it and does not fly to this refuge is unhappy.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Book 11.10</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;There is no nature that is inferior to art, for the arts imitate the nature of things. But if this is so, that nature which is the most perfect and the most comprehensive of all natures cannot fall short of the skill of art. Now all arts do the inferior things for the sake of the superior; therefore the universal nature does so, too.</p></blockquote>

<p>Book 11.27</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The Pythagoreans bid us in the morning look to the heavens that we may be reminded of those bodies that continually do the same things and in the same manner perform their work, and also be reminded of their purity and nudity. For there is no veil over a star.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Book 5.16 (The Best for Last)</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Such are your habitual thoughts, such also will be the character of your mind; for the soul is dyed by the thoughts. Dye it then with a continuous series of such thoughts as these&hellip;&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Finally, I didn&rsquo;t take down the quote for this. But something very valuable I learned from this book is: If you&rsquo;re ashamed too ashamed to tell others about what you&rsquo;ve done. Then learn and don&rsquo;t do the same thing in the future.</p>

<p>Inspired by Jesca&rsquo;s <a href="https://linesforthoughts.wordpress.com/">Lines For Thoughts</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backpacking Japan: Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/08/15/japan-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-15T19:15:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/08/15/japan-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s incredible how fast the months can pass when you&rsquo;re having fun! As the trip came to a close we headed further into Japan to explore Osaka and Hiroshima before heading back to Tokyo. We actually went back to Tokyo earlier than we had planned, since it was just that incredible!</p>

<p><img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/train_fuji.jpg" title="'train_fuji.jpg'" ></p>

<p>We caught a pretty good view of Mount Fuji as we sped by on the Shinkansen.</p>

<!-- more -->




<h3> Osaka </h3>


<p>Tsukumen, or Dipping Noodles. Right next to our airbnb, came by here a couple times
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_tsukumen.jpg" title="'osaka_tsukumen.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Japans Supercuts, $10 for a 10 minute haircut
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_qb_house.jpg" title="'osaka_qb_house.jpg'" ></p>

<p>These $1 clear umbrellas were everywhere
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_sea_of_umbrellas.jpg" title="'osaka_sea_of_umbrellas.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Glico man!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_glico_man.jpg" title="'osaka_glico_man.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Pachinko, Japanese videogame slots
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_pachinko.jpg" title="'osaka_pachinko.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Met up with some of Amber&rsquo;s Highschool friends and ate a lot of raw food
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_dinner_raw_more.jpg" title="'osaka_dinner_raw_more.jpg'" ></p>

<p>My first taiyaki, redbean. I&rsquo;d go on to try custard, curry, etc filled
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_first_taiyaki.jpg" title="'osaka_first_taiyaki.jpg'" ></p>

<p>This turtle has been all over the world!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_castle_turtle.jpg" title="'osaka_castle_turtle.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Amber, I and Osaka Castle. It was golden week so very crowded and active. We saw performers and a rock band
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_castle_group.jpg" title="'osaka_castle_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Favorite sushi place, used huge slabs of fish
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_sushi_monster.jpg" title="'osaka_sushi_monster.jpg'" ></p>

<p>What dreams are made of
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_sushi_wow.jpg" title="'osaka_sushi_wow.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Amber had met Tetsu somewhere in Southeast Asia (he&rsquo;s Tatsu&rsquo;s friend). He showed us around Osaka
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_tetsuyoshi.jpg" title="'osaka_tetsuyoshi.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Took us to a place under the subway where they boiled everything. Had whale for the first time.
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/4_osaka/osaka_tsukidashi.JPG" title="'osaka_tsukidashi.JPG'" ></p>

<h3> Hiroshima </h3>


<p>Our hotels view, right in the center of Hiroshima
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_hotel_view_festival.jpg" title="'hiroshima_hotel_view_festival.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Our hotel happened to be in the middle of the Hiroshima Flower Festival
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_flower_festival_1.jpg" title="'hiroshima_flower_festival_1.jpg'" ></p>

<p>There were parades all day
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_flower_festival_2.jpg" title="'hiroshima_flower_festival_2.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Woah
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_flower_festival_3.jpg" title="'hiroshima_flower_festival_3.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Hundreds of huge paper cranes. Well, ten hundred would be a good guess.
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_flower_festival_4.jpg" title="'hiroshima_flower_festival_4.jpg'" ></p>

<p>There was food everywhere too
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_flower_festival_food.jpg" title="'hiroshima_flower_festival_food.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Mazemen place right next to our hotel
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_okkundo_mazemen.jpg" title="'hiroshima_okkundo_mazemen.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Sobering abomb museum
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_museum_abomb.jpg" title="'hiroshima_museum_abomb.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Genbaku (&ldquo;A-Bomb&rdquo;) Dome, directly below the epicenter of the abomb detonation
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_abomb_center.jpg" title="'hiroshima_abomb_center.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Hiroshima style Okanomiyaki (over noodles)
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_dinner_okanomiyaki.jpg" title="'hiroshima_dinner_okanomiyaki.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Day trip to Itsukushima Island </h3>


<p>Pretty sweet gate, looks cooler when the tide rises though
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_itsukushima_gate.jpg" title="'hiroshima_itsukushima_gate.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Messing around at the shrine
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_itsukushima_pose.jpg" title="'hiroshima_itsukushima_pose.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Well known for seafood, you can find people digging for seafood on the beach
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_itsukushima_shrine_oysters.jpg" title="'hiroshima_itsukushima_shrine_oysters.jpg'" ></p>

<p>At night once the tide had come in a little
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/5_hiroshima/hiroshima_itsukushima_shrine_tide.jpg" title="'hiroshima_itsukushima_shrine_tide.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Back to Tokyo </h3>


<p>Were planning on staying in Hiroshima for a couple days longer, but couldn&rsquo;t wait to get back to Tokyo!</p>

<p>Tokyo Stations Character Street. Full of anime shops: Shonen Jump, Pokemon, Miyazaki, Eggy, etc
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_character_street.jpg" title="'tokyo_character_street.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Ameyayokocho market in Ueno. Found a lot of great stuff, they had Red Wings, Americaya, Samurai, Flathead, etc&hellip;
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_ueno_ameyoko_market.jpg" title="'tokyo_ueno_ameyoko_market.jpg'" ></p>

<p>This place was recommended to us by a couple people, was delicious and filling
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_ueno_ameyoko_gogo_curry.jpg" title="'tokyo_ueno_ameyoko_gogo_curry.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Parade forming outside our curry place
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_ueno_ameyoko_animals.jpg" title="'tokyo_ueno_ameyoko_animals.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Megumi and Masa, Amber&rsquo;s friends that she had met in Australia
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_lunch_tempura_group.jpg" title="'tokyo_lunch_tempura_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Went to a wellknown place specializing in Tempura
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_lunch_tempura_megumi_masa.jpg" title="'tokyo_lunch_tempura_megumi_masa.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Tempura!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_lunch_tempura.jpg" title="'tokyo_lunch_tempura.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Disney Sea </h3>


<p>The only Disney Sea in the world, located right next to Japan&rsquo;s Disneyland
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_disney_sea.jpg" title="'tokyo_disney_sea.jpg'" ></p>

<p>I was brought here with promises of Aquariums and penguins, but it turned out to be pretty alright
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_disney_sea_alladin.jpg" title="'tokyo_disney_sea_alladin.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Character Signings were pretty cool
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_disney_sea_stitch.jpg" title="'tokyo_disney_sea_stitch.jpg'" ></p>

<p>We met Mrs Incredible
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_disney_sea_mrsincredible.jpg" title="'tokyo_disney_sea_mrsincredible.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Fantasia Light show!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_disney_sea_lightshow.jpg" title="'tokyo_disney_sea_lightshow.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Exploring Tokyo </h3>


<p>Went to see the infamous Gundam Wing
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_odaiba_gundam.jpg" title="'tokyo_odaiba_gundam.jpg'" ></p>

<p>There was an little Jpop concert next door
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_odaiba_jpop.jpg" title="'tokyo_odaiba_jpop.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Went to Ikekukuro&rsquo;s Pokemon Mega Center
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_ikebukuro_pokemon.jpg" title="'tokyo_ikebukuro_pokemon.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Got her Charizard Pikachu
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_ikebukuro_pokemon_center.jpg" title="'tokyo_ikebukuro_pokemon_center.jpg'" ></p>

<p>The line was too long the first time we tried to go here, came earlier the next day and got ourselves some delicious sushi
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_shibuya_sushi_midori.JPG" title="'tokyo_shibuya_sushi_midori.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Tokyo Skytree and me
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_skytree.jpg" title="'tokyo_skytree.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Shinjuku, the sketchy redlight district. Our hotel was here
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_shinjuku.jpg" title="'tokyo_shinjuku.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Stereotypical and offensive Robot Restuarant
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_shinjuku_robot_restuarant.jpg" title="'tokyo_shinjuku_robot_restuarant.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Waited three hours in the morning cold, was sick for a few weeks, but that was incredible sushi
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_tsukiji_line.jpg" title="'tokyo_tsukiji_line.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Sea Urchin, mmmmmm
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_tsukiji_sushi_dai_urchin.JPG" title="'tokyo_tsukiji_sushi_dai_urchin.JPG'" ></p>

<p>And those slabs of tuna in the back&hellip;
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_tsukiji_sushi_dai.jpg" title="'tokyo_tsukiji_sushi_dai.jpg'" ></p>

<p>My last day in Japan, Metropolitan Observation Deck looking out over Tokyo
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_metropolitan_observation_deck.jpg" title="'tokyo_metropolitan_observation_deck.jpg'" ></p>

<p>You can see tokyo skytree if you look at the orange/white tower slightly to the right of the center one.
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_metropolitan_deck_tokyo_tower.jpg" title="'tokyo_metropolitan_deck_tokyo_tower.jpg'" ></p>

<p>My last meal had to be sushi
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_midori_last_sushi.jpg" title="'tokyo_midori_last_sushi.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Met a guy who let me try some whale and his million dollar watch. That&rsquo;s my $350 one behind it
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_millionaire_watch.jpg" title="'tokyo_millionaire_watch.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Listened to this street performer on the streets of Shibuya while I waited until it was time to train out to haneda airport
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_shibuya_drummer.jpg" title="'tokyo_shibuya_drummer.jpg'" ></p>

<p>The famous crossing you see in all those movies
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/6_tokyo_again/tokyo_shibuya_famous_crossing.jpg" title="'tokyo_shibuya_famous_crossing.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Goodbye Asia
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/misc/good_bye.jpg" title="'good_bye.jpg'" ></p>

<p>And welcome home
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/misc/back_home.jpg" title="'back_home.jpg'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backpacking Japan]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/06/30/japan/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-30T17:30:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/06/30/japan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/nara_temple_todai-ji.jpg" title="'nara_temple_todai-ji.jpg'" ></p>

<p>While Vietnam was more of an adventure, Japan fell on the vacation side. The hospitality was incredible and the hostels felt like 5 star hotels. The cuisine was full of novel tastes and textures. The culture was quirky and energetic. Most importantly though, I got to visit one of my homelands, something I&rsquo;ve always wanted to do.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The clouds over the Sea of Japan
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/misc/flight_in.jpg" title="'flight_in.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Hong Kong Express saved me a lot of money this trip
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/misc/plane_ticket.jpg" title="'plane_ticket.jpg'" ></p>

<p>The beginning of a long trip from the airport to hostel
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/misc/welcome_to_japan.jpg" title="'welcome_to_japan.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Tokyo </h3>


<p>We stayed at a hostel in Akihabara, well known for its Otaku culture. Walk a couple stories up or down and you&rsquo;d start finding some weird stuff
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/tokyo_akihabara.jpg" title="'tokyo_akihabara.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Quick breakfast at our favorite 24 hour place before heading out to explore
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/tokyo_akihabara_lunch.jpg" title="'tokyo_akihabara_lunch.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Hachiko, after his owner died he continued to run out here day after day to meet him. Naturally there&rsquo;s a film adaptation
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/shibuya_hachiko.jpg" title="'shibuya_hachiko.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Zach&rsquo;s friend Mio took us to an Izakaya
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/shibuya_izakaya.jpg" title="'shibuya_izakaya.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Met Emi as an exchange student at UCSD several years ago, we met again in her territory
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/shibuya_emi.jpg" title="'shibuya_emi.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Apparently Spumoni&rsquo;s are very popular in Japan
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/shibuya_spumoni_manhattan.jpg" title="'shibuya_spumoni_manhattan.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Roppongi is the party district of Tokyo. Clubs here stay open until 5am, just in time to catch the first subways
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/roppongi_vanity.jpg" title="'roppongi_vanity.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Kamakura trip out of Tokyo </h3>


<p>Took a day trip to Kamakura. Tatsu, who Amber had met in Thailand (?), came and hung out with us. This was the largest buddha in the world when it was constructed in the 1200s.
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/kamakura_daibutsu_buddha_group.jpg" title="'kamakura_daibutsu_buddha_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Cute statues in the garden
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/kamakura_hasedera_temple_cute.jpg" title="'kamakura_hasedera_temple_cute.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Poor the water on the statue for good luck!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/kamakura_hasedera_temple_luck.jpg" title="'kamakura_hasedera_temple_luck.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Met Mio and her friend for all you can eat and drink hotpot
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/tokyo_ayce.jpg" title="'tokyo_ayce.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Walked around in Shinjuku redlight after dinner
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/1_tokyo/shinjuku_strip_club.jpg" title="'shinjuku_strip_club.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Kyoto </h3>


<p>Subway brought us up in the center of a Japanese university, everyone was so fashionable!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/kyoto_imedegawa_university.jpg" title="'kyoto_imedegawa_university.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Imperial palace, if you walk on the wrong side of the canal an alarm will go off&hellip;
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/kyoto_imperial_palace.jpg" title="'kyoto_imperial_palace.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Group shot at Imperial Palace
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/kyoto_imperial_palace_group.jpg" title="'kyoto_imperial_palace_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Nasty Crab Miso (sperm) sushi
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/kyoto_crab_miso.jpg" title="'kyoto_crab_miso.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Had to creep for awhile, but stalked ourself a Geisha
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/kyoto_geisha.jpg" title="'kyoto_geisha.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Walking through what seems like a Kyoto suburb
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/kyoto_neighborhood.jpg" title="'kyoto_neighborhood.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Lots of orange gates
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/inari_temple_walk_to_tofukuji.jpg" title="'inari_temple_walk_to_tofukuji.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Inari the fox
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/inari_fushimi_shrine.jpg" title="'inari_fushimi_shrine.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Arashiyama trip out of Kyoto </h3>


<p>Arashiyama, land of the monkeys
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/arashiyama_group.jpg" title="'arashiyama_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Walking down the river
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/arashiyama_river.jpg" title="'arashiyama_river.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Can feed the monkeys from within the cage
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/arashiyama_monkey_hut.jpg" title="'arashiyama_monkey_hut.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Monkey Selfie with humans
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/arashiyama_monkey_group.jpg" title="'arashiyama_monkey_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Bamboo Path
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/arashiyama_bamboo_path.jpg" title="'arashiyama_bamboo_path.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Pond of Dragon, my phones new lock screen
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/arashiyama_pond_of_dragon.jpg" title="'arashiyama_pond_of_dragon.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Nara trip out of Kytoto </h3>


<p>Nara, land of the deer
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/nara_mascot.jpg" title="'nara_mascot.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Randomly saw some turtles on the walk over
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/nara_turtles.jpg" title="'nara_turtles.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Selfie with a photogenic deer. They&rsquo;re normally not allowed to have antlers but I guess this one was well behaved.
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/nara_deer_group.jpg" title="'nara_deer_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Wow
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/nara_temple_todai-ji_pretty.jpg" title="'nara_temple_todai-ji_pretty.jpg'" ></p>

<p>One of the big Buddhas inside
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/nara_temple_todai-ji_buddha.jpg" title="'nara_temple_todai-ji_buddha.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Sunset
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/2_kyoto/nara_temple_todai-ji_view.jpg" title="'nara_temple_todai-ji_view.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Kinosake </h3>


<p>Morizuya Ryokan, probably the favorite place I stayed over the whole trip. Got to sleep on tatami mats and wear yukatas
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/3_kinosake/kinosake_yukata.jpg" title="'kinosake_yukata.jpg'" ></p>

<p>They even gave me one
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/3_kinosake/kinosake_me.jpg" title="'kinosake_me.jpg'" ></p>

<p>There was a private cave onsen in Morizuya itself
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/3_kinosake/kinosake_morizuya_onsen_cave.jpg" title="'kinosake_morizuya_onsen_cave.jpg'" ></p>

<p>And they had a rock turtle who was about my age
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/3_kinosake/kinosake_morizuya_turtle.jpg" title="'kinosake_morizuya_turtle.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Brought us breakfast
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/3_kinosake/kinosake_breakfast.jpg" title="'kinosake_breakfast.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Satonyu, one of the four onsens we went to. Had outdoor pools, steam rooms, waterfalls, everything!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/3_kinosake/kinosake_onsen_satonoyu.jpg" title="'kinosake_onsen_satonoyu.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Freaky sandfish
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/3_kinosake/kinosake_sandfish.jpg" title="'kinosake_sandfish.jpg'" ></p>

<p>View over Kinosake and the Maruyama River flowing out to the Sea of Japan
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/japan/3_kinosake/kinosake_view.jpg" title="'kinosake_view.jpg'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backpacking Hong Kong]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/05/23/hong-kong/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-23T17:30:08-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/05/23/hong-kong</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tai_mei_tuk/tai_mei_tuk_biking.jpg" title="'tai_mei_tuk_biking.jpg'" ></p>

<p>I had originally planned to go to China during this period but decided a couple weeks would not be nearly enough time and didn&rsquo;t want to waste a six month, relatively expensive visa on it. So I decided to go to Hong Kong instead.</p>

<!-- more -->




<h3> Hong Kong </h3>


<p>Some cool Hong Kong apartments we saw on the bus ride in
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/misc/apartments.jpg" title="'apartments.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Dim sum
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/misc/dim_sum.jpg" title="'dim_sum.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Dim sum at lunch, the crowd is trying to get to the food cart
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/misc/dim_sum_cart.jpg" title="'dim_sum_cart.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Picked up some Kinder Joys
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/misc/kinder_joy.JPG" title="'kinder_joy.JPG'" ></p>

<p>My Kinder Joy Toy family
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/misc/kinder_joy_toys.JPG" title="'kinder_joy_toys.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Spiderman on an adventure
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/misc/kinder_joy_spiderman_adventures.JPG" title="'kinder_joy_spiderman_adventures.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Hong Kong is pretty watch crazy, went to try on a classic
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/misc/omega_speedmaster.JPG" title="'omega_speedmaster.JPG'" ></p>

<h3> Mongkok </h3>


<p>Amber&rsquo;s Mini High School reunion with Leo and me
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/mongkok/mongkok_group.jpg" title="'mongkok_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Ended up near one of those protests we see one the news back home
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/mongkok/mongkok_protest.JPG" title="'mongkok_protest.JPG'" ></p>

<p>And more dim sum of course
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/mongkok/more_dim_sum.jpg" title="'more_dim_sum.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Tai Mei Tuk </h3>


<p>Claire took us to Tai Mei Tuk for a fun time biking through the scenic landscape
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tai_mei_tuk/tai_mei_tuk_more_biking.jpg" title="'tai_mei_tuk_more_biking.jpg'" ></p>

<p>She then took us to a nearby wet market
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tai_mei_tuk/seafood_market.JPG" title="'seafood_market.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Various fish
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tai_mei_tuk/seafood_market_fish.JPG" title="'seafood_market_fish.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Geoducks and Abalone!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tai_mei_tuk/seafood_market_geoduck.jpg" title="'seafood_market_geoduck.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Top floor had a bunch of restuarants, got a full seafood dinner
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tai_mei_tuk/seafood_market_dinner.jpg" title="'seafood_market_dinner.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Ocean Park </h3>


<p>Had wanted to see an aquarium, so headed to Ocean Park
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/ocean_park/ocean_park_group.jpg" title="'ocean_park_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>So hundreds of different kinds of sea life, this was the most awkward one
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/ocean_park/ocean_park_awkward_fish.jpg" title="'ocean_park_awkward_fish.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Watching this guy eat was incredible
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/ocean_park/ocean_park_panda_eating.jpg" title="'ocean_park_panda_eating.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Nice view of Hong Kong from the Gondola
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/ocean_park/ocean_park_view.jpg" title="'ocean_park_view.jpg'" ></p>

<p>There were some exhilarating rides
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/ocean_park/ocean_park_rides.jpg" title="'ocean_park_rides.jpg'" ></p>

<h3> Amber's Family </h3>


<p>Met up with some of Ambers relatives
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/amber_family/amber_family_group.jpg" title="'amber_family_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>They took us to hotpot at the &lsquo;Very Good Restuarant&rsquo;
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/amber_family/hotpot_family.jpg" title="'hotpot_family.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Had some incredible abalone
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/amber_family/hotpot_abalone.JPG" title="'hotpot_abalone.JPG'" ></p>

<p>The next day they took us to the beach, which happened to be next to a dogpark
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/amber_family/beach_dogpark.jpg" title="'beach_dogpark.jpg'" ></p>

<p>We messed around with this crab for awhile
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/amber_family/crab.jpg" title="'crab.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Then to the peak, a shopping mall where you can look out over all of Hong Kong. Unfortunately it was cloudy&hellip;
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/amber_family/the_peak.JPG" title="'the_peak.JPG'" ></p>

<h3> Tsim Sha Tsui (TST) </h3>


<p>Hong Kongs Walk of Stars
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tst/tst_walk_of_stars.JPG" title="'tst_walk_of_stars.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Found this on the way back to our hotel one night
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tst/tst_fountain.jpg" title="'tst_fountain.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Can&rsquo;t believe this was a 5 minute walk from our hotel, spent a lot of time here! They had a light show every night
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/tst/tst_skyline_lightshow.JPG" title="'tst_skyline_lightshow.JPG'" ></p>

<h3> Kowloon and Causeway Bay</h3>


<p>Amber left for Singapore a day early to catch her prebooked flight to Japan, so I wandered around. Found this at a mall.
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/causeway_bay/causeway_bay_avengers.JPG" title="'causeway_bay_avengers.JPG'" ></p>

<p>They&rsquo;re adorable! Got myself Ironman and a Thor for my little brother
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/causeway_bay/causeway_bay_avengers_bobbleheads.JPG" title="'causeway_bay_avengers_bobbleheads.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Visited a nunnery and found an awesome temple
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/kowloon/kowloon_chi_lin_nunnery.JPG" title="'kowloon_chi_lin_nunnery.JPG'" ></p>

<p>And there was a beautiful garden next door
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/kowloon/kowloon_nan_lian_garden.JPG" title="'kowloon_nan_lian_garden.JPG'" ></p>

<h3> Farewell Hong Kong and off to Japan </h3>


<p>And off to Japan, time flies and so do I
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/hong_kong/misc/airport.JPG" title="'airport.JPG'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backpacking Vietnam: Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/05/13/vietnam-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-13T16:06:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/05/13/vietnam-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/7_sapa/sapa_looking_away.jpg" title="'sapa_looking_away.jpg'" ></p>

<p>After a couple weeks Andreas' Visa expired and he headed back to the U.S. The rest of us had planned to head to Indonesia at this point but decided we wanted more time in Vietnam. Zach, Quynh, and Sherrie headed south for the sunny beach resort of Nha Trang while Amber and I set off west for the green hills of Sapa before heading south back into central Vietnam.</p>

<!-- more -->




<h3>Sapa</h3>


<p>The van that took us to the bus broke down but eventually we made it to this awesome and comfortable sleeper bus
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/7_sapa/sapa_sleeper_bus.JPG" title="'sapa_sleeper_bus.JPG'" ></p>

<p>The view from our hotel, gorgeous!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/7_sapa/sapa_hotel_view.jpg" title="'sapa_hotel_view.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Amber met Ha while traveling in Thailand, she graciously let us stay at her homestay, eat at her restuarant, wear black hmong clothes&hellip; it was an incredible experience
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/7_sapa/sapa_ha.JPG" title="'sapa_ha.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Ha&rsquo;s homestay
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/7_sapa/sapa_homestay.jpg" title="'sapa_homestay.jpg'" ></p>

<p>They made us incredible dinners
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/7_sapa/sapa_homestay_dinner.jpg" title="'sapa_homestay_dinner.jpg'" ></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s more green during rice season
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/7_sapa/sapa_vietnam.jpg" title="'sapa_vietnam.jpg'" ></p>

<p>A beautiful valley
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/7_sapa/sapa_panorama.JPG" title="'sapa_panorama.JPG'" ></p>

<h3>Phong Nha</h3>


<p>Such an idyllic place
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/8_phong_nha/phong_nha_group.jpg" title="'phong_nha_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>ECHOOO!!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/8_phong_nha/phong_nha_crazy_caves.JPG" title="'phong_nha_crazy_caves.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Exploring the caves
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/8_phong_nha/phong_nha_taking_picture.JPG" title="'phong_nha_taking_picture.JPG'" ></p>

<p>More exploring
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/8_phong_nha/phong_nha_cave.jpg" title="'phong_nha_cave.jpg'" ></p>

<p>We found someone recording a music video!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/8_phong_nha/phong_nha_famous_cave.JPG" title="'phong_nha_famous_cave.JPG'" ></p>

<p>And of course he has an entourage
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/8_phong_nha/phong_nha_entourage.JPG" title="'phong_nha_entourage.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Has to be one of the prettiest places we visited
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/8_phong_nha/phong_nha_view.JPG" title="'phong_nha_view.JPG'" ></p>

<p>BBQ pork banh mi, bought a couple extra for the road
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/8_phong_nha/phong_nha_pork_banh_mi.jpg" title="'phong_nha_pork_banh_mi.jpg'" ></p>

<h3>Hoi An</h3>


<p>A little town near Da Nang that lights up at night
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/9_hoi_an/hoi_an_bridge.jpg" title="'hoi_an_bridge.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Just a little bit touristy
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/9_hoi_an/hoi_an_cute_duck.jpg" title="'hoi_an_cute_duck.jpg'" ></p>

<p>But it&rsquo;s very appreciated, unlimited fruit and fruit juice and a room for less than $20 a night
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/9_hoi_an/misc_complimentary.jpg" title="'misc_complimentary.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Newlyweds are all over the river dropping lanterns (wishes) down the river!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/9_hoi_an/hoi_an_pretty.jpg" title="'hoi_an_pretty.jpg'" ></p>

<p>The view from the little eatery we dined at. Stayed for awhile and enjoyed the view :)
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/9_hoi_an/hoi_an_view_eatery.jpg" title="'hoi_an_view_eatery.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Leaving this wonderful country for Hong Kong and new adventures!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/9_hoi_an/misc_bye_vietnam.jpg" title="'misc_bye_vietnam.jpg'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backpacking Vietnam]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/05/02/vietnam/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-02T16:06:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/05/02/vietnam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/halong_bay.jpg" title="'Quynh's Panorama shot, halong.jpg'" ></p>

<p>When I set out on the biggest adventure of my life, I was afraid it somehow wouldn&rsquo;t match up to expectations. And expectations were high after hearing stories and having wanted to go for years. So I&rsquo;m happy to say that Vietnam was perfect, it was a crazy and exhilarating adventure of strange things and marvelous places.</p>

<p>Here are some highlights from the trip:</p>

<!-- more -->




<h3>Saigon</h3>


<p>Saigon Market
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/1_saigon/saigon_market.jpg" title="'saigon_market.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Our first meal in Vietnam
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/1_saigon/saigon_first_meal_vietnam.jpg" title="'saigon_market_first_meal.jpg'" ></p>

<p>View from our airbnb apartment
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/1_saigon/saigon_airbnb_view.jpg" title="'saigon_airbnb.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Airbnb apartment falling apart
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/1_saigon/saigon_airbnb_fail.jpg" title="'saigon_airbnb_fail.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Delicous dish from the Man Beer restuarant
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/1_saigon/saigon_great_meal.jpg" title="'saigon_great_meal.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Partying it up for our last night in Saigon
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/1_saigon/saigon_last_night.JPG" title="'saigon_last_night.JPG'" ></p>

<h3>Mei Kong</h3>


<p>Quynh&rsquo;s Uncle Doctor Ho let us stay at his beautiful house
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/2_uncle_ho/uncle_ho_house.JPG" title="'uncle_ho_house.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Uncle Ho&rsquo;s special blend of whiskey, good for fertility!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/2_uncle_ho/uncle_ho_whiskey.JPG" title="'uncle_ho_whiskey.JPG'" ></p>

<p>They made us the most incredible meal
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/2_uncle_ho/uncle_ho_dinner.jpg" title="'uncle_ho_dinner.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Quynh&rsquo;s family gave us of the surrounding dragon fruit fields
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/2_uncle_ho/uncle_ho_dragon_fruit_fields.jpg" title="'uncle_ho_dragon_fruit_fields.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Then they took us to the Mei Kong delta
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/2_uncle_ho/uncle_ho_mei_kong_delta.JPG" title="'uncle_ho_mei_kong_delta.JPG'" ></p>

<p>The first of the many Buddhas of my Asia trip
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/2_uncle_ho/uncle_ho_first_buddha.jpg" title="'uncle_ho_first_buddha.jpg'" ></p>

<h3>Phu Quoc</h3>


<p>Hanging out on a beautiful beach in Vietnam!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/3_phu_quoc/phu_quoc_group.jpg" title="'phu_quoc_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Lounging
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/3_phu_quoc/phu_quoc_lounging.jpg" title="'phu_quoc_lounging.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Dinner! Eat the whole thing, even the bones
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/3_phu_quoc/phu_quoc_fish.jpg" title="'phu_quoc_fish.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Beautiful red sunset as we sip cocktails
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/3_phu_quoc/phu_quoc_sunset.jpg" title="'phu_quoc_sunset.jpg'" ></p>

<h3>Da Nang</h3>


<p>Finally have time to do some laundry
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_laundry.JPG" title="'da_nang_laundry.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Year of the Goat!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_goat.jpg" title="'da_nang_goat.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Apparently you pray to this one for health
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_buddha.jpg" title="'da_nang_buddha.jpg'" ></p>

<p>The biggest Buddha I saw the whole trip
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_lady_buddha.jpg" title="'da_nang_lady_buddha.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Taking a break while Amber practiced her photography
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_water.jpg" title="'da_nang_water.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Taking another break on the way up a granite mountain
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_break_hiking.jpg" title="'da_nang_break_hiking.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Group picture after a long hike
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_group.jpg" title="'da_nang_group.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Da Nang is pretty
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_panorama.JPG" title="'da_nang_panorama.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Our hotel&rsquo;s grand opening party, there was a band, magician, fireworks, and most importantly 50% off!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_hotel_party.jpg" title="'da_nang_hotel_party.jpg'" ></p>

<p>We went to the tallest building to celebrate our last night in Da Nang
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/4_da_nang/da_nang_party.jpg" title="'da_nang_party.jpg'" ></p>

<h3>Hanoi</h3>


<p>Stopped by Hanoi on the way to Halong
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/5_hanoi/hanoi_ho_chi_minh_pose.jpg" title="'hanoi_ho_chi_minh_pose.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Favorite bowl of pho, came here twice
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/5_hanoi/hanoi_pho.JPG" title="'hanoi_pho.JPG'" ></p>

<h3>Halong</h3>


<p>The girls and our boat
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/6_halong/halong_our_boat.JPG" title="'halong_our_boat.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Unfortunately, not the nicest day. But it was incredible nevertheless
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/6_halong/halong_boat.JPG" title="'halong_boat.JPG'" ></p>

<p>Attempting to help row
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/6_halong/halong_rowing.jpg" title="'halong_rowing.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Group picture!
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/6_halong/halong_group_picture.jpg" title="'halong_group_picture.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Surprise cave, the first of many caves
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/6_halong/halong_surprise_cave.jpg" title="'halong_surprise_cave.jpg'" ></p>

<p>Happened to see this while looking for a place to eat
<img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/vietnam/6_halong/halong_pc_bang.JPG" title="'halong_pc_bang.JPG'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asia Trip 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/03/01/asia-trip-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-01T15:06:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/03/01/asia-trip-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/images/intro_asia/packing.jpg" title="'packing.jpg'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Ruby on Rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2014/06/13/learning-ruby-on-rails/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-13T17:16:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2014/06/13/learning-ruby-on-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Under Construction</h2>

<h3>Table of Contents</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#learningrails">Learning Rails</a></li>
<li><a href="#apps">Apps</a></li>
<li><a href="#octopress">Octopress</a></li>
<li><a href="#whatilearned">What I Learned</a></li>
<li><a href="#conclusion">Conclusion</a></li>
<li><a href="#technologies">Technologies behind this Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="#source">Source</a></li>
</ul>


<p><a name="introduction"></a></p>

<h3>Introduction</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always wanted a personal website, for such a long time that I can&rsquo;t even remember the original reason. But it always felt so difficult, like there would be hoop after hoop to jump through. And there were, but I found that each hoop was very easy to jump through, with fantastic resources and frameworks doing almost the entirety of the leg work.</p>

<p>This was one of my first truly independent projects. Prior to this I had always had a partner, professor, TA, etc to fall back on if I got stuck. So this project was stepping out of my comfort zone, which is always difficult. But as I&rsquo;ve found, pushing those boundaries has great reward and brings a certain feeling of personal pride and independence.</p>

<p><a name="learningrails"></a></p>

<h3>Learning Rails</h3>

<p>To learn Ruby on Rails I made use of <a href="https://www.codecademy.com/learn/ruby">Codeacademy Ruby Guide</a>, <a href="http://ruby.railstutorial.org/">Michael Hartl&rsquo;s Ruby on Rails Tutorial</a>, and <a href="http://railscasts.com/">Railscast</a>. Codeacademy was fairly basic and I think is catered towards complete beginners. But looking through there I found some good basic guides to brush up on things like git or commandline. Michael Hartl&rsquo;s tutorial was incredible and even after finishing it I would come back and use it as a reference guide. For things that Michael Hartl&rsquo;s guide couldn&rsquo;t cover I would look through Railscast.</p>

<p><a name="apps"></a></p>

<h3>Apps</h3>

<p>I started off wanting to build a blog, so I modified Hartl&rsquo;s code for that purpose. Building a dynamic mysql blogged webapp. I wanted to try something a little bit different as well so I build a <a href="upload-app.nicklau.io/">Photo Uploading app</a>. It seemed like it would be difficult but by utilitizing Ruby on Rails gems it turned out to be easy. The Cloudinary gem was quick to setup and did all the heavy lifting, offering a way to upload and store images in the cloud.</p>

<p>I wasn&rsquo;t entirely happy with the blog though, as a one person blog I found the dynamic nature to be redundant. Then I got lucky browsing around the internet reading blogs. I found that this <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">&lsquo;Octopress Blog: A Blogging Framework for Hackers&rsquo;</a> came up repeatedly, so I decided to check it out. Turns out it was exactly what I was looking for. I thought Ruby on Rails did a lot of the work for me, but Octopress utilizes Jekyll to do even more. It generates posts, provides tools like improved image tags. And above all it is static, so no need for a database, one less thing to worry about breaking. It also takes care of the UI, and lets you download template themes for a personal flare. Or quickly plugin fun additions like Disqus or Google Analytics. Above all its static, so I don&rsquo;t have to worry about the model part of MVC.</p>

<p><a name="whatilearned"></a></p>

<h3>What I Learned</h3>

<p>I learned far more than just Ruby and Ruby on Rails. The nature of an independent project is that every step you have to search for the proper tool to do this or that, and you end up finding a lot of new things. For example, I fell in love with the three window (commandline, editor, browser) workflow. I got more comfortable with using commandline debuggers, helping to reduce my dependence on the bloated IDEs I had been stuck with in college. The commandline is very romanticized and it was awesome to get to know it better.</p>

<p>I found out how easy things are, especially since Ruby on Rails has such a strong community. Heroku makes it effortless to deploy your app, gems like New Relic can monitor your app with less than 10 lines and 10 minutes of work. When I wanted to speed my app up, it took copying and pasting in two short blurbs and installing a gem. The hours I spent building a login system from scratch in Michael Hartl&rsquo;s tutorial was replaced instantaneously with the Devise gem (the understanding I got from the tutorial can not be replaced though). I remember setting the devise gem up and looking for the generated code (I thought it was a scaffold). But after checking git and seeing that there were actually no changes to the source&hellip; that the system actually worked!</p>

<p>This is where I started to understand how much of programming is simply reading and interface and plugging to pieces together. How layers like ActiveRecord could be laid on top of your database so that it could handle anything from postgresql, mysql, etc. How REST could be laid on top off resources and interact with them through universal verbs/actions.</p>

<p>I learned to write user stories and plan out my code better before I started typing (school projects would generally provide structure). I learned to use git better, to branch on features and merge them back only once completed. And that they were only completed once that had an automated test suite. And to use Test Driven Development to make sure they that new features were fulfilling their test cases. I had theoretically known what MVC and REST were, but here I got some first hand experience with them. Things I take for granted like how to write in Markdown.</p>

<p>University didn&rsquo;t expose me to the most interesting language, there were a few weeks of ocaml and python, but asides from that mostly Java and C++. I found Ruby to be very refreshing, being able to do things like
<a href="http://blog.jayfields.com/2008/03/ruby-inject.html">inject</a>. Or easy list comprehension and array splicing like python. Or how as a dynamic language, it would have really cool methods like &lsquo;method_missing()&rsquo;, lazy evaluation, or would put &lsquo;?&rsquo; or &lsquo;!&rsquo; if it returned a boolean or modified data, respectively. How it had an REPL to play around with an idea, or first class functions (procs, lambdas, closures) intead of the mess that Java callbacks are. It also enforced the idea that despite all the differences, at their root all the languages were very similar. Sure there would be some different syntax, typing, or libraries but in the end it all came down to the idea of structured programming: that everything could be done with a combination of sequence, selection, iteration.</p>

<p>I bought a domain and learned how to use its DNS, which was actually one of the biggest hassles. There isn&rsquo;t a wealth of helpful information online about hosting, and it&rsquo;s very unhelpful that providers work differently so the guides you find aren&rsquo;t entirely applicable. However, the longer it takes you to find something out, the better you understand it, so no harm there.</p>

<p>I learned random invaluable things like Lorem Ipsum and the origins of foobar.</p>

<p><a name="conclusion"></a></p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>Overall I found it very analagous to backpacking around Asia. When you first set out its terrifying, you have no one to rely on. But you learn and quickly find everything to be very easy. You meet incredible people who want to help you. You discover new things about yourself and come out of it a stronger and more independent individual.</p>

<p><a name="technologies"></a></p>

<h3>Technologies behind this Blog</h3>

<p>This blog webapp utilizes the technologies/services:</p>

<ul>
<li>Ruby on Rails obviously!</li>
<li>Octopress, powered by Jekyll. A blogging framework for hackers.</li>
<li>gandi.net for hosting and dns services.</li>
<li>Rack::Cache for faster loading</li>
<li>Heroku for hosting online as well as the New Relic addon to stop the dyno from idling.</li>
<li>Devise for user, session, and password management.</li>
<li>Bootstrap to make things look pretty since I’m no css wizard.</li>
<li>Rspec and Capybara for quick automated testing.</li>
</ul>


<p><a name="source"></a></p>

<h3>Source</h3>

<ul>
<li>Source on <a href="https://github.com/nmlau/octopress">github</a></li>
<li>Hosted at <a href="http://www.nicklau.io/">nicklau.io</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on Clarity]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2014/05/13/thoughts-on-clarity/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-13T23:16:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2014/05/13/thoughts-on-clarity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s why stories appeal to us. They give us the clarity and simplicity our real lives lack&rdquo; - Patrick Rothfuss. Since I love stories, whether they are from books or movies or tv&hellip; this quote struck me. However, I think that the hunt for clarity and simplicity applies beyond stories to everything that I love, to all the hobbies that I enjoy. I do not expect to ever understand life enough that I might claim that it is simple. However, I will certainly try. I feel that my best chance is to pick small pockets of life as hobbies and over a lifetime of learning, achieve a high level of understanding (or clarity).</p>

<p>I have always loved clarity. When I played hockey in high school, I loved starting a rush up the ice, all the possibilities laid bare before me. Or studying for a final as I could feel all the information consolidating, seeing how interconnected all the details were and understanding the flow of the subject matter. Thus, I loved games, learning their inner workings and obsessing over them until I could see several steps ahead. I loved learning because if you studied hard enough and read deep enough into the subject then there was no need to memorize, it would become natural and simply make sense.</p>

<p>But games come and go. The one constant has become programming, it is the ultimate hobby since I can get paid for doing it and spend my next 30-40 years exploring its nuisances under the guise of a career. I&rsquo;ll be surrounded with others who have spent decades studying and learn from them. There will be no slacking since I&rsquo;ll be disciplined to spending 40 hours a week. And yes, I will balance it with my personal life and other hobbies. Ultimately though, I see it as my greatest hope for achieving clarity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
