<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: shortcuts | Nicks Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/categories/shortcuts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-26T20:34:49-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicholas Lau]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favorite Tools and Tricks]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/03/favorite-tools-and-tricks/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-03T00:26:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/12/03/favorite-tools-and-tricks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was showing two of my engineer buddies something on my laptop when I realized they didn&rsquo;t know how to shortcut between tabs. It blew my mind that people don&rsquo;t know these things, which got my thinking about all the little tips and tricks I&rsquo;ve picked up over the years. I ended up making a list&hellip; so I figured I might as well share it. I&rsquo;ll throw on a quick summary for why I use all these things. For example:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Google</em>, Really really good search engine. A strong alternative to Bing if you&rsquo;re willing to give up the $125/year that Microsoft will give you for clicks.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ve mostly found these through annoyance at minor inconveniences, whether they be multiple keystrokes or the laborious task of moving my hands to the keyboard and back.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Chrome Shortcuts</h3>

<ul>
<li>Remove item from search bar and history, opt+cmd+del</li>
<li>Switching between tabs, shift+opt+{} or ctrl+shift+tab</li>
<li>Jumping between tabs, cmd+(0-9)</li>
<li>Moving to address bar, cmd+L</li>
</ul>


<h3>Gmail Shortcuts (have to enable them)</h3>

<ul>
<li>Refresh inbox, U</li>
<li>Move between messages, j/k</li>
<li>Archive and Move between messages, {/}</li>
<li>Move to search bar, /</li>
<li>Open message, o</li>
<li>Move between Folders, g+(i for inbox)(t for sent)(l for label)(s for starred)(a for all)</li>
<li>Compose, c</li>
<li>Send, cmd+enter</li>
</ul>


<h3>Chrome Extensions</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Vimium</em>, I couldn&rsquo;t live without this one. It lets you use chrome with vim inspired shortcuts. Hit &rsquo;d' to go down half a page, &lsquo;k&rsquo; to scroll up, &lsquo;gi&rsquo; to move cursor to a textarea then &lsquo;tab&rsquo; to move to the next textarea, etc.</li>
<li><em>Papaly</em>, I have two tabs pinned&hellip; gmail and papaly. Papaly lets me save links in a quick and organized manner, letting me keep my browser uncluttered.</li>
<li><em>Empty New Tab Page</em>, Because it cleans up your interface ever so slightly, &ldquo;a clean room is a clean mind&rdquo;.</li>
<li><em>Imagus</em>, hover to see full size image. Have it configured to show image on shift press.</li>
<li><em>goo.gl URL Shortener</em>, this is very particular to my workflow. Whenever I find something valuable on the internet, I&rsquo;ll throw a quick summary and it&rsquo;s goog.gl link on a plain text to review later.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Privacy</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Ghostery</em>, Ghostery blocks 3rd party trackers, make sure to disable GhostRank.</li>
<li><em>TrackMeNot</em>, clicks every ad (but doesn&rsquo;t load them) to obfuscate your actual activity.</li>
<li><em>uBlockOrigin</em>, uBlockOrigin, largely superior Adblock Plus. More efficient.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Software</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Flux</em>, reduces eyestrain by adapting your computer screen to the time of day. Takes some adjusting to. But after that you won&rsquo;t be able to live without it.</li>
<li><em>Moom</em>, window management, lets me move my windows anywhere I want with an efficient hotkey. Mandatory if you&rsquo;re working with larger monitors (I have a 27" and 24").</li>
<li><em>VPN</em>, lets me feel safe when I&rsquo;m on public wifi. Was especially useful when I backed around Asia. I personally use Private Internet Access (PIA), one of the bigger providers.</li>
<li><em>Copy Clip</em>, clipboard manager for os x. It&rsquo;s free, why not?</li>
<li><em>Google Spreadsheets</em>, have several of these setup for subjects that require more organization. Is conveniently synced between phone and computers.</li>
<li><em>Pomodoro Timer</em>, more for my workflow. I work on tasks in 30 minute chunks so its perfect.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Knowledge base</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Sublime Text</em>, have it opened with entire Dropbox directory. cmd+shift+f executes an interactive grep-like search, makes it very easy to find what I&rsquo;m looking for. cmd+t lets me quickly open whatever file I want.</li>
<li><em>Nebulous for iOS</em>, plain text editor and Dropbox compatibility. Lets me view and edit my knowledge base. Great for my todo lists and to productively kill time when I&rsquo;m waiting in line.</li>
<li><em>Dropbox</em>, keeps everything synced. Although I did have to pay for more storage.</li>
<li><em>Org mode</em>, incredible! Plan to integrate this into workflow shortly.</li>
<li><em>Evernote</em>, you all know what this is. I&rsquo;m not it&rsquo;s biggest fan, eventually I want to move to an org mode + dropbox + sublime/nebulous workflow. But for now, I use its reminders to re-expose me to particularily interesting pieces of knowledge. Huge issues include: inconvenient exporting, no multiple hierachies of notes/notebooks, ads everywhere, general bugginess.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Sublime Text</h3>

<ul>
<li>ctrl+cmd+up/down arrows, swap rows up and down.</li>
<li>ctrl+shift+up/down arrows, quickly spawn multiple cursors for some efficient editing.</li>
<li>cmd+k then cmd+b, hide/show sidebar</li>
<li>ctrl+shift+k, delete the current line your cursor is on</li>
<li>Many many more, but I don&rsquo;t want to go overboard</li>
</ul>


<h3>OS X</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Spotlight</em>, cmd+space. Let&rsquo;s you find anything on your computer quickly and conveniently. Whether it&rsquo;s an application, file, widget.</li>
<li><em>Hot Corners</em>, move the mouse to bottom left or right corner to put my laptop to sleep. Lets me take faster bathroom breaks at the coffee shop.</li>
<li>Remapping Caps to Control at OS level (Modifier Keys). Especially useful for the Command Line Interface. Who uses Caps Lock anyways.</li>
<li>PLEASE NEVER MOVE THROUGH TEXT BY HOLDING THE ARROW KEYS (and try to avoid the mouse). cmd+left/right arrows, move to beginning or end of line. option+left/right arrow, move a word at a time, similar to vim&rsquo;s &lsquo;w&rsquo; and &lsquo;b&rsquo; commands.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Peace of Mind</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Crashplan</em>, backs up my computer to a remote location every night while I&rsquo;m sleeping. I backup with my harddrive weekly for a local backup. So unless the right data center and my house burn down simultaneously I&rsquo;m fine.</li>
<li><em>Mint</em>, free personal budgeting application. I used to constantly worry about whether I was getting mischarged, having my credit cards stolen, or paying fees I shouldn&rsquo;t be. With this I can check every couple days and never have to worry.</li>
<li><em>1Password</em>, just in case I forget. Sync my keychain over dropbox so it&rsquo;s available in case of emergencies.</li>
</ul>


<h3>App Specific</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Mint Mojito</em>, improves ui for mint. You can cut out sections you don&rsquo;t want, like: recommendations, ads, etc&hellip;</li>
<li><em>Google Calendar Scroll Disabler</em>, because the trackpad is way too sensitive and I often found myself a year ahead of where I wanted to be.</li>
<li><em>The Camelizer</em>, tracks Amazon prices. Let&rsquo;s you see if you&rsquo;re getting a good deal or should wait. Can set price watches that will notify you when the price drops to what you&rsquo;re willing to pay. Along this note, using ifttt to watch rss feeds or using slickdeals deal watchers is really effective as well.</li>
<li><em>Reddit Enhancement Suite</em>, I can&rsquo;t remember what it was like to not have this.</li>
<li><em>Download FB Album mod</em>, lets you download albums off Facebook, in case they ever go out of business.</li>
<li><em>Boomerang for Gmail</em>, Lets you program mail to be sent at certain times. Nice when you&rsquo;re doing email at 3am, but want it sent out at a reasonable time.</li>
<li>Facebook: <em>News Feed Blocker</em>, <em>Facebook Unseen</em> (I know this should be in App-Specific&hellip; but for real). When you open facebook to jump on the messenger, the feed is less likely to draw you in&hellip; and unseen so that you can read messages without beening inclined to answer them until it&rsquo;s more convenient. Remember when the &lsquo;seen at 4:21&rsquo; feature was new and everyone despised it?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
