<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: a tale of two cities | Nicks Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/categories/a-tale-of-two-cities/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-17T12:57:19-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicholas Lau]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Tale of Two Cities by Charles Dickens]]></title>
    <link href="http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/10/27/a-tale-of-two-cities-by-charles-dickens/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-27T14:17:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://octopress.nicksdevspot.com/blog/2015/10/27/a-tale-of-two-cities-by-charles-dickens</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some of my favorite quotes from A Tale of Two Cities by Charles Dickens:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;I should like to ask you: -Does your childhood seem far off? Do the days when you sat at your mother&rsquo;s knee, seem days of very long ago?</p>

<p>Responding to his softened maner, Mr. Lorry answered:</p>

<p>Twenty years back, yes; at this time of my life, no. For, as I draw closer and closer to the end, I travel in the circle, nearer and nearer to the beginning. It seems to be one of the kind smoothings and preparings of the way. My heart is touched now, by many remembrances that had long fallen asleep, of my pretty young mother (and I so old!), and by many associations of the days when what we call the World was not so real with me, and my faults were not confirmed in me."</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<!-- -->


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The wretched wife of the innocent man thus doomed to die, fell under the sentence, as if she had been mortally stricken. But, she uttered no sound; and so strong was the voice within her, representing that it was she of all the world who must uphold him in his misery and not augment it, that it quickly raised her, even from that shock.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
